<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"> <channel><title>mbailey/notes</title><description>Things I might need again.</description><link>https://mike.bailey.net.au/</link><atom:link href="https://mike.bailey.net.au/feed_rss_created.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><managingEditor>Mike Bailey</managingEditor><docs>https://github.com/mbailey/mbailey.github.io</docs><language>en</language> <pubDate>Tue, 11 Mar 2025 14:01:36 -0000</pubDate> <lastBuildDate>Tue, 11 Mar 2025 14:01:36 -0000</lastBuildDate> <ttl>1440</ttl> <generator>MkDocs RSS plugin - v1.17.1</generator> <image> <url>https://mike.bailey.net.au/assets/favicon.png</url> <title>mbailey/notes</title><link>https://mike.bailey.net.au/</link> </image> <item> <title>Eat Something New Every Day</title> <description>&lt;p&gt;On &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.abc.net.au/tv/programs/redesign-my-brain-with-todd-sampson/&#34;&gt;Redesign My Brain&lt;/a&gt;, Todd Sampson took on the challenge of eating somethingnew each day in order to get his brain working more creatively. I decided to trythis as well to see if I notice any changes to my thinking.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Fruit seems like an obvious place to start for me as I only eat three of them: apples, bananas and mandarins.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2 id=&#34;jan&#34;&gt;Jan&lt;a class=&#34;headerlink&#34; href=&#34;#jan&#34; title=&#34;Permanent link&#34;&gt;&amp;para;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;01 Kiwifruit # I solved the kiwifruit for myself.02 Apricot # I cheated and watched &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=FaWNNbCRuNw&#34;&gt;a walkthrough&lt;/a&gt;. Do you eat the skin?&lt;/p&gt;</description><link>https://mike.bailey.net.au/blog/2014/01/02/eat-something-new-every-day/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=feed-syndication</link> <pubDate>Sun, 23 Feb 2025 09:08:55 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://mike.bailey.net.au/feed_rss_created.xml">mbailey/notes</source><comments>https://mike.bailey.net.au/blog/2014/01/02/eat-something-new-every-day/#__comments</comments><guid isPermaLink="true">https://mike.bailey.net.au/blog/2014/01/02/eat-something-new-every-day/</guid> </item> <item> <title>Truth about Edinburgh Gardens NYE</title> <description>&lt;p&gt;What happens when more 15,000 revellers converge on an inner city Melbournepark to ring in the new year with no perimeter fencing, byo drugs/alcohol andjust 12 police officers on duty?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;A potential horror story of violence and destruction didn&#39;t eventuate butthis hasn&#39;t stopped the media from describing it as such.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;There are over different 15,000 versions of NYE in Edinburgh Gardens 2014 and Isuspect most people had a pretty fun time. The fact it turned out to be alargely peaceful celebration despite the absence of any effective crowdcontrol seems both newsworthy and worthy of further discussion.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;Ms Fristacky says local residents had varied views of the New Year&#39;s Eveparty. &#34;Quite a few residents who attended said it was a great night, theyenjoyed it, it was 20,000 people mostly peaceful, yes there were someincidents, but they were isolated.&#34;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.abc.net.au/local/audio/2014/01/02/3919817.htm&#34;&gt;City of Yarra Mayor quoted by ABC&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;Reading between the lines, the night sounds a bit like a night at an open airmusic festival like Meredith or Golden Plains. Events like these show us thatwhile we will never be completely rid of dickheads, most people want to be goodto each other.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Misrepresentation of the evening and villification it&#39;s participants has spreadrighteous indignation far beyond residents of the parks gentrified surrounds.Yarra Council is now facing increased pressure to crack down on park users.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2 id=&#34;trashing-the-gardens&#34;&gt;&#39;Trash&#39;ing the Gardens&lt;a class=&#34;headerlink&#34; href=&#34;#trashing-the-gardens&#34; title=&#34;Permanent link&#34;&gt;&amp;para;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;We were told the park was &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.theage.com.au/victoria/council-counts-cost-of-trashed-park-after-dance-party-20140101-3063f.html&#34;&gt;trashed&lt;/a&gt;. While this brings thoughts of vandalism andpermanent damage, reporters were actually referring to litter, most of whichwas all picked up and removed by Council staff and volunteers by sunset on 1Jan.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Now don&#39;t get me wrong, there was a whole lot of litter. The place was a messbut one man&#39;s trash is another man&#39;s treasure and the indignation inspiringimagery was media gold for the evening news and daily papers.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;What kind of people would do this?&#34; src=&#34;../../../../images/edinburgh-gardens-rubbish.jpg&#34; /&gt;&lt;em&gt;What kind of people would do this?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;&#34;inadequate lighting and excessive crowding also appeared to dissuade peoplefrom using the rubbish bins and toilet facilities provided, with significantcomplaints about public urination;&#34;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.yarracity.vic.gov.au/DownloadDocument.ashx?DocumentID=10222&#34;&gt;Council Report&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;Oh yeah, people partying in the dark&#34; src=&#34;../../../../images/boys-in-park.png&#34; /&gt;&lt;em&gt;Oh yeah, people partying in the dark&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Music festivals like Meredith and Golden Plains see attendees cleaning up themess from the night before when the sun rises.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2 id=&#34;fence-climbing&#34;&gt;Fence Climbing&lt;a class=&#34;headerlink&#34; href=&#34;#fence-climbing&#34; title=&#34;Permanent link&#34;&gt;&amp;para;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Climbing can be fun but the recently installed tennis court fences aren&#39;t verystrong. The top bars slipped under the weight of people climbing on them. TheHerald Sun reported this as &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.heraldsun.com.au/news/victoria/happy-new-year-victoria-parties-into-2014/story-fni0fit3-1226792796876&#34;&gt;vandalism&lt;/a&gt;. By these standards youraverage two year old is a wanton vandal.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://instagram.com/p/ilnmIHDklK/&#34;&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;Darwin was Right&#34; src=&#34;../../../../images/fence-climbing.png&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;Darwin was Right&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2 id=&#34;casualties&#34;&gt;Casualties&lt;a class=&#34;headerlink&#34; href=&#34;#casualties&#34; title=&#34;Permanent link&#34;&gt;&amp;para;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;Ambulance staff set up an emergency triage area in the park, where theytreated about 20 people.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Most were treated for alcohol-related problems, while others suffered cutsfrom broken glass in the park.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.abc.net.au/news/2014-01-01/paramedics-outraged-by-dangerous-nye-party/5180670&#34;&gt;&#34;Paramedics Outraged&#34;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;Meredith and Golden Plains are two music festivals where you can bring your own alcohol but have a strict NO GLASS POLICY.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;There were two violent acts reported. A man lost several teeth when he was&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.theage.com.au/victoria/mans-teeth-smashed-in-attack-during-edinburgh-gardens-new-years-eve-party-20140102-306ji.html&#34;&gt;punched in the face&lt;/a&gt; and a seventeen year old boy was arrestedafter he allegedly &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.theage.com.au/victoria/messy-new-years-eve-in-edinburgh-gardens-north-fitzroy-20140101-305ag.html&#34;&gt;punched a female police officer&lt;/a&gt; in the face.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I don&#39;t think anyone has worked out a solution to dickheads but MMF try:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;Festivals at the Meredith Supernatural Amphitheatre have a No Dickhead Policy.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Essentially this is a self-policing policy whereby ‘the dickhead’ is notcelebrated at the festival. Dickheads or people involved in dickheadbehaviour will usually find that a solid citizen will firmly but politelyinform them that their dickhead behaviour is not admired or appreciated. TheDickhead will usually realise they are being a dickhead and pull their headin. If not, our Helpers or Staff or even Security might make a discreetintervention.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;So if you are a Dickhead, this festival isn’t for you.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://2013.mmf.com.au/what-goes-on/dickhead-policy/&#34;&gt;MMF No Dickhead Policy&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;h2 id=&#34;hey-rupert-stop-bashing-our-youth&#34;&gt;Hey Rupert, Stop Bashing Our Youth&lt;a class=&#34;headerlink&#34; href=&#34;#hey-rupert-stop-bashing-our-youth&#34; title=&#34;Permanent link&#34;&gt;&amp;para;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Demonising our youth may sell papers but what does it do to our social fabric?Crafting words that stir up moral panic doesn&#39;t make life easier for anyone.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The sky is not falling and the connected generations are not falling for your lies.&lt;/p&gt;</description><link>https://mike.bailey.net.au/blog/2014/01/06/truth-about-edinburgh-gardens-nye/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=feed-syndication</link> <pubDate>Sun, 23 Feb 2025 09:08:55 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://mike.bailey.net.au/feed_rss_created.xml">mbailey/notes</source><comments>https://mike.bailey.net.au/blog/2014/01/06/truth-about-edinburgh-gardens-nye/#__comments</comments><guid isPermaLink="true">https://mike.bailey.net.au/blog/2014/01/06/truth-about-edinburgh-gardens-nye/</guid> </item> <item> <title>night friendly lighting</title> <description></description><link>https://mike.bailey.net.au/blog/2014/01/07/night-friendly-lighting/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=feed-syndication</link> <pubDate>Sun, 23 Feb 2025 09:08:55 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://mike.bailey.net.au/feed_rss_created.xml">mbailey/notes</source><comments>https://mike.bailey.net.au/blog/2014/01/07/night-friendly-lighting/#__comments</comments><guid isPermaLink="true">https://mike.bailey.net.au/blog/2014/01/07/night-friendly-lighting/</guid> </item> <item> <title>How to Save Money</title> <description>&lt;p&gt;Are you price conscious in your everyday spending? A lot of us aren&#39;t for thebasic reason that it consumes brain cycles for little percieved reward.Quitting smoking led to an adjustment in the way I value money. Forking out $20 aday for something the literally goes up in smoke can make saving $5 a day onparking seem pretty irrelevant.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In considering my monthly spend I found a number of ways I could spend lesswithout any real impact on my quality of life. Perhaps some of these couldhelp you?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2 id=&#34;stop-smoking-start-vaping-600mon&#34;&gt;Stop Smoking, Start Vaping ($600/mon)&lt;a class=&#34;headerlink&#34; href=&#34;#stop-smoking-start-vaping-600mon&#34; title=&#34;Permanent link&#34;&gt;&amp;para;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;I&#39;d describe myself as dependant on nicotine. My pack a day habit was costingme $600 a month. I&#39;m now using a vapouriser to get my nicotine fix for $20 amonth.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2 id=&#34;park-10-minutes-walk-from-office-110mon&#34;&gt;Park 10 minutes walk from office ($110/mon)&lt;a class=&#34;headerlink&#34; href=&#34;#park-10-minutes-walk-from-office-110mon&#34; title=&#34;Permanent link&#34;&gt;&amp;para;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Adding 20 minutes of gentle exercise to my otherwise sedentary existance saves mea packet.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2 id=&#34;stop-buying-takeaway-coffee-88mon&#34;&gt;Stop buying takeaway coffee ($88/mon)&lt;a class=&#34;headerlink&#34; href=&#34;#stop-buying-takeaway-coffee-88mon&#34; title=&#34;Permanent link&#34;&gt;&amp;para;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;We have coffee machines at work. It&#39;s free and I&#39;m a good milk frother.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2 id=&#34;find-cheaper-car-insurance-35mon&#34;&gt;Find cheaper car insurance ($35/mon)&lt;a class=&#34;headerlink&#34; href=&#34;#find-cheaper-car-insurance-35mon&#34; title=&#34;Permanent link&#34;&gt;&amp;para;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;I was surprised how easy this one was. Thanks Google.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2 id=&#34;buy-supermarket-milk-30mon&#34;&gt;Buy supermarket milk ($30/mon)&lt;a class=&#34;headerlink&#34; href=&#34;#buy-supermarket-milk-30mon&#34; title=&#34;Permanent link&#34;&gt;&amp;para;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;I was under the mistaken impression that the branded milk was better.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;iframe width=&#34;560&#34; height=&#34;315&#34; src=&#34;//www.youtube.com/embed/IIOvRO8k7uI&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;h2 id=&#34;pay-less-for-petrol-12mon&#34;&gt;Pay Less for Petrol ($12/mon)&lt;a class=&#34;headerlink&#34; href=&#34;#pay-less-for-petrol-12mon&#34; title=&#34;Permanent link&#34;&gt;&amp;para;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;There&#39;s about a 10% difference between low and high prices for petrol dependingon when in the cycle you fill up. I can save $6 on a 40 litre tank by filling upat the right time.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;A tank lasts me 2 weeks. If you need to fill more often YMMV.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;ACCC report on Australian petrol price cycle&#34; src=&#34;http://www.accc.gov.au/sites/www.accc.gov.au/files/fuelwatch/melbourne.jpg&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Vendors try to mix it up but the graph above is updated daily and gives a goodidea of when it&#39;s a good time to buy. They also have &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.accc.gov.au/consumers/petrol-diesel-and-lpg/recent-city-petrol-prices&#34;&gt;petrol prices for other Australian states&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2 id=&#34;dont-buy-premium-fuel-unless-your-car-needs-it-8mon&#34;&gt;Don&#39;t buy premium fuel unless your car needs it ($8/mon)&lt;a class=&#34;headerlink&#34; href=&#34;#dont-buy-premium-fuel-unless-your-car-needs-it-8mon&#34; title=&#34;Permanent link&#34;&gt;&amp;para;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;I&#39;ve not a petrol head and haven&#39;t even researched this one very well but startedsaving around $4 on a tank of fuel by not paying for premium.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Australian petrol stations market several types of unleaded petrol. They tend tobe 91, 95 and 98 &#34;octane&#34;. I don&#39;t know much about fuel and the higher numberscost more so I tended to choose 95 or 98 thinking I must be getting more fromit.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;It turns out some cars (European) require high octane fuels or their performancedeteriorates. I checked my Subaru manual and it said I was fine using 91 octane fuel.&lt;/p&gt;</description><link>https://mike.bailey.net.au/blog/2014/01/08/how-to-save-money/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=feed-syndication</link> <pubDate>Sun, 23 Feb 2025 09:08:55 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://mike.bailey.net.au/feed_rss_created.xml">mbailey/notes</source><comments>https://mike.bailey.net.au/blog/2014/01/08/how-to-save-money/#__comments</comments><guid isPermaLink="true">https://mike.bailey.net.au/blog/2014/01/08/how-to-save-money/</guid> </item> <item> <title>Smoking: Prevention &amp; Treatment</title> <category>smoking</category> <description>&lt;p&gt;When it comes to life threatening situations, prevention and treatment servedifferent purposes and importantly, different populations.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;For example, responses to the AIDS epidemic in the 1980s included campaigns toeducate the public on how to reduce their risk of contracting HIV as well asresearch into a cure. Effective treatment options were discovered which greatlyimprove the prognosis for infected people with access to them.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;During this same period, our public health bodies seem to have focussed on prevent buthave failed to identify effective methods for people who want to stop smoking. The&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.quit.org.au/preparing-to-quit/choosing-best-way-to-quit&#34;&gt;methods many organisations promote&lt;/a&gt; see reported relapse rates of around80% within the first six months.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;These include:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Cold Turkey (Quitting abruptly)&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Nicotine Replacement Products (Patches, gum, lozenge, mouth spray, inhalator)&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Quitting Medication (Champix or Zyban)&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;It&#39;s unfathomable that ineffective treatments for tobacco addiction are beingpromoted while little effort is made to identify effective methods for peopleto use to stop smoking.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Australia&#39;s &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.nationaldrugstrategy.gov.au/internet/drugstrategy/publishing.nsf/Content/national_ts_2012_2018&#34;&gt;National Tobacco Strategy&lt;/a&gt; lists a number of objectives whichinclude:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;prevent uptake of smoking&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;encourage and assist as many smokers as possible to quit as soon as possible, and prevent relapse&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;These objectives assist two separate populations, never smokers and smokers.The needs of people who smoke cannot be served meaningfully while we do nothave effective methods for them to quit.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The reduction in smoking rates in Australia this century have been mainly due to anincrease in never-smokers with the percentage of ex-smokers staying faily constant.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.aihw.gov.au/alcohol-and-other-drugs/ndshs-2013/&#34;&gt;National Drug Strategy Household Survey 2013&lt;/a&gt; - Tobacco Smoking Status&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;one-quarter (24%) of the population were ex-smokers and this has remainedfairly stable since 1998 when the proportion of ex-smokers first exceeded theproportion smoking daily&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#39;one-quarter (24%) of the population were ex-smokers and this has remained fairly stable since 1998 when the proportion of ex-smokers first exceeded the proportion smoking daily&#39; &#39;one-quarter (24%) of the population were ex-smokers and this has remained fairly stable since 1998 when the proportion of ex-smokers first exceeded the proportion smoking daily&#39;&#34; src=&#34;../../../../images/ndshs-2013-tobacco-smoking-status-1991-2013.png&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Australia&#39;s smoking bans, tax hikes, advertising campaigns and other efforts may havecontributed to reduced uptake of smoking but do not appear to have made quitting easier.While focussing on the children, there have been little change in daily smoking seenamong people aged 60 or older this century.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;daily smokers&#34; src=&#34;../../../../images/ndshs-2013-daily-smokers-2001-2013.png&#34; /&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;We know that most smokers &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/15799597&#34;&gt;regret taking up the habit&lt;/a&gt;. We need to acknowledgethe high relapse rates for currently promoted smoking cessation methods andget to work identifying effective alternatives.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In 2013, around 40% of Australians who smoke heavily tried to give upunsuccessfully (&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.aihw.gov.au/alcohol-and-other-drugs/ndshs-2013/&#34;&gt;NDSHS&lt;/a&gt;). We don&#39;t need to be convinced we should quit, weneed to know how.&lt;/p&gt;</description><link>https://mike.bailey.net.au/blog/2015/10/25/smoking-prevention--treatment/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=feed-syndication</link> <pubDate>Sun, 23 Feb 2025 09:08:55 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://mike.bailey.net.au/feed_rss_created.xml">mbailey/notes</source><comments>https://mike.bailey.net.au/blog/2015/10/25/smoking-prevention--treatment/#__comments</comments><guid isPermaLink="true">https://mike.bailey.net.au/blog/2015/10/25/smoking-prevention--treatment/</guid> </item> <item> <title>Semantic CloudFormation Parameter Values</title> <category>aws</category> <category>cloudformation</category> <description>&lt;p&gt;Here&#39;s a &lt;strong&gt;pure Cloudformation&lt;/strong&gt; solution to two annoyances I encounter whenmanaging AWS CloudFormation Parameters. It allows you to &lt;em&gt;optionally&lt;/em&gt; specifyexported CloudFormation Output values in your CloudFormation Parameters.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Most resources I deploy on AWS are managed via CloudFormation using reusabletemplates and custom Parameters. Configuring the Parameters often requireslooking up resource identifiers for VPCs, Subnets, Route Tables and the like.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Here are the Parameters for a stack that creates routes for a VPC Peering Connection:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;code&gt;&lt;a id=&#34;__codelineno-0-1&#34; name=&#34;__codelineno-0-1&#34; href=&#34;#__codelineno-0-1&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;[&lt;a id=&#34;__codelineno-0-2&#34; name=&#34;__codelineno-0-2&#34; href=&#34;#__codelineno-0-2&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; {&lt;a id=&#34;__codelineno-0-3&#34; name=&#34;__codelineno-0-3&#34; href=&#34;#__codelineno-0-3&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &amp;quot;ParameterKey&amp;quot;: &amp;quot;RemoteSubnet1CIDR&amp;quot;,&lt;a id=&#34;__codelineno-0-4&#34; name=&#34;__codelineno-0-4&#34; href=&#34;#__codelineno-0-4&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &amp;quot;ParameterValue&amp;quot;: &amp;quot;10.0.38.0/24&amp;quot;&lt;a id=&#34;__codelineno-0-5&#34; name=&#34;__codelineno-0-5&#34; href=&#34;#__codelineno-0-5&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; },&lt;a id=&#34;__codelineno-0-6&#34; name=&#34;__codelineno-0-6&#34; href=&#34;#__codelineno-0-6&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; {&lt;a id=&#34;__codelineno-0-7&#34; name=&#34;__codelineno-0-7&#34; href=&#34;#__codelineno-0-7&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &amp;quot;ParameterKey&amp;quot;: &amp;quot;RemoteSubnet2CIDR&amp;quot;,&lt;a id=&#34;__codelineno-0-8&#34; name=&#34;__codelineno-0-8&#34; href=&#34;#__codelineno-0-8&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &amp;quot;ParameterValue&amp;quot;: &amp;quot;10.0.39.0/24&amp;quot;&lt;a id=&#34;__codelineno-0-9&#34; name=&#34;__codelineno-0-9&#34; href=&#34;#__codelineno-0-9&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; },&lt;a id=&#34;__codelineno-0-10&#34; name=&#34;__codelineno-0-10&#34; href=&#34;#__codelineno-0-10&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; {&lt;a id=&#34;__codelineno-0-11&#34; name=&#34;__codelineno-0-11&#34; href=&#34;#__codelineno-0-11&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &amp;quot;ParameterKey&amp;quot;: &amp;quot;RouteTable1&amp;quot;,&lt;a id=&#34;__codelineno-0-12&#34; name=&#34;__codelineno-0-12&#34; href=&#34;#__codelineno-0-12&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &amp;quot;ParameterValue&amp;quot;: &amp;quot;rtb-01234567&amp;quot;&lt;a id=&#34;__codelineno-0-13&#34; name=&#34;__codelineno-0-13&#34; href=&#34;#__codelineno-0-13&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; },&lt;a id=&#34;__codelineno-0-14&#34; name=&#34;__codelineno-0-14&#34; href=&#34;#__codelineno-0-14&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; {&lt;a id=&#34;__codelineno-0-15&#34; name=&#34;__codelineno-0-15&#34; href=&#34;#__codelineno-0-15&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &amp;quot;ParameterKey&amp;quot;: &amp;quot;RouteTable2&amp;quot;,&lt;a id=&#34;__codelineno-0-16&#34; name=&#34;__codelineno-0-16&#34; href=&#34;#__codelineno-0-16&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &amp;quot;ParameterValue&amp;quot;: &amp;quot;rtb-12345678&amp;quot;&lt;a id=&#34;__codelineno-0-17&#34; name=&#34;__codelineno-0-17&#34; href=&#34;#__codelineno-0-17&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; },&lt;a id=&#34;__codelineno-0-18&#34; name=&#34;__codelineno-0-18&#34; href=&#34;#__codelineno-0-18&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; {&lt;a id=&#34;__codelineno-0-19&#34; name=&#34;__codelineno-0-19&#34; href=&#34;#__codelineno-0-19&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &amp;quot;ParameterKey&amp;quot;: &amp;quot;VpcPeeringConnection&amp;quot;,&lt;a id=&#34;__codelineno-0-20&#34; name=&#34;__codelineno-0-20&#34; href=&#34;#__codelineno-0-20&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &amp;quot;ParameterValue&amp;quot;: &amp;quot;pcx-11111111111111111&amp;quot;&lt;a id=&#34;__codelineno-0-21&#34; name=&#34;__codelineno-0-21&#34; href=&#34;#__codelineno-0-21&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; }&lt;a id=&#34;__codelineno-0-22&#34; name=&#34;__codelineno-0-22&#34; href=&#34;#__codelineno-0-22&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-annoyances&#34;&gt;The Annoyances&lt;a class=&#34;headerlink&#34; href=&#34;#the-annoyances&#34; title=&#34;Permanent link&#34;&gt;&amp;para;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;I love CloudFormation but the file above annoys me for two reasons:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li&gt;It doesn&#39;t convey much about these route tables or subnets&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;p&gt;These routes are for the &lt;code&gt;bma-prod&lt;/code&gt; VPC to get to &lt;code&gt;internal&lt;/code&gt; subnets on &lt;code&gt;failmode-prod&lt;/code&gt;. In order to work that out you would need to lookup each value. That&#39;s toil.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li&gt;I had to query AWS to find these values&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;p&gt;When creating the Parameters file for the &lt;code&gt;non-prod&lt;/code&gt; account, I would need to lookup all these values again. That&#39;s toil.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3 id=&#34;semantic-cloudformation-parameter-values&#34;&gt;Semantic CloudFormation Parameter Values&lt;a class=&#34;headerlink&#34; href=&#34;#semantic-cloudformation-parameter-values&#34; title=&#34;Permanent link&#34;&gt;&amp;para;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;The VPCs I deploy export &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.aws.amazon.com/AWSCloudFormation/latest/UserGuide/using-cfn-stack-exports.html&#34;&gt;Stack Output&lt;/a&gt; values that can be imported by other Stacks.These are given unique names by prepending the stack name to the value identifer.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I resolved both annoyances above by updating my Parameters file to refer to these values:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;code&gt;&lt;a id=&#34;__codelineno-1-1&#34; name=&#34;__codelineno-1-1&#34; href=&#34;#__codelineno-1-1&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;[&lt;a id=&#34;__codelineno-1-2&#34; name=&#34;__codelineno-1-2&#34; href=&#34;#__codelineno-1-2&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; {&lt;a id=&#34;__codelineno-1-3&#34; name=&#34;__codelineno-1-3&#34; href=&#34;#__codelineno-1-3&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &amp;quot;ParameterKey&amp;quot;: &amp;quot;RemoteSubnet1CIDR&amp;quot;,&lt;a id=&#34;__codelineno-1-4&#34; name=&#34;__codelineno-1-4&#34; href=&#34;#__codelineno-1-4&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &amp;quot;ParameterValue&amp;quot;: &amp;quot;import:vpc-failmode-prod-SUBNETINTERNAL1CIDR&amp;quot;&lt;a id=&#34;__codelineno-1-5&#34; name=&#34;__codelineno-1-5&#34; href=&#34;#__codelineno-1-5&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; },&lt;a id=&#34;__codelineno-1-6&#34; name=&#34;__codelineno-1-6&#34; href=&#34;#__codelineno-1-6&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; {&lt;a id=&#34;__codelineno-1-7&#34; name=&#34;__codelineno-1-7&#34; href=&#34;#__codelineno-1-7&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &amp;quot;ParameterKey&amp;quot;: &amp;quot;RemoteSubnet2CIDR&amp;quot;,&lt;a id=&#34;__codelineno-1-8&#34; name=&#34;__codelineno-1-8&#34; href=&#34;#__codelineno-1-8&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &amp;quot;ParameterValue&amp;quot;: &amp;quot;import:vpc-failmode-prod-SUBNETINTERNAL2CIDR&amp;quot;&lt;a id=&#34;__codelineno-1-9&#34; name=&#34;__codelineno-1-9&#34; href=&#34;#__codelineno-1-9&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; },&lt;a id=&#34;__codelineno-1-10&#34; name=&#34;__codelineno-1-10&#34; href=&#34;#__codelineno-1-10&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; {&lt;a id=&#34;__codelineno-1-11&#34; name=&#34;__codelineno-1-11&#34; href=&#34;#__codelineno-1-11&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &amp;quot;ParameterKey&amp;quot;: &amp;quot;RouteTable1&amp;quot;,&lt;a id=&#34;__codelineno-1-12&#34; name=&#34;__codelineno-1-12&#34; href=&#34;#__codelineno-1-12&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &amp;quot;ParameterValue&amp;quot;: &amp;quot;import:vpc-bma-prod-RTBPRIVATE1&amp;quot;&lt;a id=&#34;__codelineno-1-13&#34; name=&#34;__codelineno-1-13&#34; href=&#34;#__codelineno-1-13&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; },&lt;a id=&#34;__codelineno-1-14&#34; name=&#34;__codelineno-1-14&#34; href=&#34;#__codelineno-1-14&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; {&lt;a id=&#34;__codelineno-1-15&#34; name=&#34;__codelineno-1-15&#34; href=&#34;#__codelineno-1-15&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &amp;quot;ParameterKey&amp;quot;: &amp;quot;RouteTable2&amp;quot;,&lt;a id=&#34;__codelineno-1-16&#34; name=&#34;__codelineno-1-16&#34; href=&#34;#__codelineno-1-16&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &amp;quot;ParameterValue&amp;quot;: &amp;quot;import:vpc-bma-prod-RTBPRIVATE2&amp;quot;&lt;a id=&#34;__codelineno-1-17&#34; name=&#34;__codelineno-1-17&#34; href=&#34;#__codelineno-1-17&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; },&lt;a id=&#34;__codelineno-1-18&#34; name=&#34;__codelineno-1-18&#34; href=&#34;#__codelineno-1-18&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; {&lt;a id=&#34;__codelineno-1-19&#34; name=&#34;__codelineno-1-19&#34; href=&#34;#__codelineno-1-19&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &amp;quot;ParameterKey&amp;quot;: &amp;quot;VpcPeeringConnection&amp;quot;,&lt;a id=&#34;__codelineno-1-20&#34; name=&#34;__codelineno-1-20&#34; href=&#34;#__codelineno-1-20&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &amp;quot;ParameterValue&amp;quot;: &amp;quot;pcx-11111111111111111&amp;quot;&lt;a id=&#34;__codelineno-1-21&#34; name=&#34;__codelineno-1-21&#34; href=&#34;#__codelineno-1-21&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; }&lt;a id=&#34;__codelineno-1-22&#34; name=&#34;__codelineno-1-22&#34; href=&#34;#__codelineno-1-22&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;h3 id=&#34;adding-support-to-the-stack-template&#34;&gt;Adding Support to the Stack Template&lt;a class=&#34;headerlink&#34; href=&#34;#adding-support-to-the-stack-template&#34; title=&#34;Permanent link&#34;&gt;&amp;para;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;This pure CloudFormation pattern supports both of the Parameter styles shown above. We define someconditions that look for &lt;code&gt;import:&lt;/code&gt; at the start of a Parameter value and thisdetermines whether it should be imported or simply used as a string.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;code&gt;&lt;a id=&#34;__codelineno-2-1&#34; name=&#34;__codelineno-2-1&#34; href=&#34;#__codelineno-2-1&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;AWSTemplateFormatVersion: &amp;#39;2010-09-09&amp;#39;&lt;a id=&#34;__codelineno-2-2&#34; name=&#34;__codelineno-2-2&#34; href=&#34;#__codelineno-2-2&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Description: VPC Peering Routes&lt;a id=&#34;__codelineno-2-3&#34; name=&#34;__codelineno-2-3&#34; href=&#34;#__codelineno-2-3&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Parameters:&lt;a id=&#34;__codelineno-2-4&#34; name=&#34;__codelineno-2-4&#34; href=&#34;#__codelineno-2-4&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; VpcPeeringConnection:&lt;a id=&#34;__codelineno-2-5&#34; name=&#34;__codelineno-2-5&#34; href=&#34;#__codelineno-2-5&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; AllowedPattern: ^pcx-[a-f0-9]+$&lt;a id=&#34;__codelineno-2-6&#34; name=&#34;__codelineno-2-6&#34; href=&#34;#__codelineno-2-6&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; ConstraintDescription: Must be a valid VPC peering ID&lt;a id=&#34;__codelineno-2-7&#34; name=&#34;__codelineno-2-7&#34; href=&#34;#__codelineno-2-7&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; Description: VPC Peering connection ID&lt;a id=&#34;__codelineno-2-8&#34; name=&#34;__codelineno-2-8&#34; href=&#34;#__codelineno-2-8&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; MinLength: &amp;#39;12&amp;#39;&lt;a id=&#34;__codelineno-2-9&#34; name=&#34;__codelineno-2-9&#34; href=&#34;#__codelineno-2-9&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; MaxLength: &amp;#39;21&amp;#39;&lt;a id=&#34;__codelineno-2-10&#34; name=&#34;__codelineno-2-10&#34; href=&#34;#__codelineno-2-10&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; Type: String&lt;a id=&#34;__codelineno-2-11&#34; name=&#34;__codelineno-2-11&#34; href=&#34;#__codelineno-2-11&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; RemoteSubnet1CIDR:&lt;a id=&#34;__codelineno-2-12&#34; name=&#34;__codelineno-2-12&#34; href=&#34;#__codelineno-2-12&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; Description: CIDR range of Remote Internal subnet 1&lt;a id=&#34;__codelineno-2-13&#34; name=&#34;__codelineno-2-13&#34; href=&#34;#__codelineno-2-13&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; Type: String&lt;a id=&#34;__codelineno-2-14&#34; name=&#34;__codelineno-2-14&#34; href=&#34;#__codelineno-2-14&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; RemoteSubnet2CIDR:&lt;a id=&#34;__codelineno-2-15&#34; name=&#34;__codelineno-2-15&#34; href=&#34;#__codelineno-2-15&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; Description: CIDR range of Remote Internal subnet 2&lt;a id=&#34;__codelineno-2-16&#34; name=&#34;__codelineno-2-16&#34; href=&#34;#__codelineno-2-16&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; Type: String&lt;a id=&#34;__codelineno-2-17&#34; name=&#34;__codelineno-2-17&#34; href=&#34;#__codelineno-2-17&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; RouteTable1:&lt;a id=&#34;__codelineno-2-18&#34; name=&#34;__codelineno-2-18&#34; href=&#34;#__codelineno-2-18&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; Description: Local Route Table 1&lt;a id=&#34;__codelineno-2-19&#34; name=&#34;__codelineno-2-19&#34; href=&#34;#__codelineno-2-19&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; Type: String&lt;a id=&#34;__codelineno-2-20&#34; name=&#34;__codelineno-2-20&#34; href=&#34;#__codelineno-2-20&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; RouteTable2:&lt;a id=&#34;__codelineno-2-21&#34; name=&#34;__codelineno-2-21&#34; href=&#34;#__codelineno-2-21&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; Description: Local Route Table 2&lt;a id=&#34;__codelineno-2-22&#34; name=&#34;__codelineno-2-22&#34; href=&#34;#__codelineno-2-22&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; Type: String&lt;a id=&#34;__codelineno-2-23&#34; name=&#34;__codelineno-2-23&#34; href=&#34;#__codelineno-2-23&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a id=&#34;__codelineno-2-24&#34; name=&#34;__codelineno-2-24&#34; href=&#34;#__codelineno-2-24&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Conditions:&lt;a id=&#34;__codelineno-2-25&#34; name=&#34;__codelineno-2-25&#34; href=&#34;#__codelineno-2-25&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; ImportRemoteSubnet1CIDR: !Equals [ &amp;quot;import&amp;quot;, !Select [ 0, !Split [ &amp;quot;:&amp;quot;, !Ref RemoteSubnet1CIDR ] ] ]&lt;a id=&#34;__codelineno-2-26&#34; name=&#34;__codelineno-2-26&#34; href=&#34;#__codelineno-2-26&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; ImportRemoteSubnet2CIDR: !Equals [ &amp;quot;import&amp;quot;, !Select [ 0, !Split [ &amp;quot;:&amp;quot;, !Ref RemoteSubnet2CIDR ] ] ]&lt;a id=&#34;__codelineno-2-27&#34; name=&#34;__codelineno-2-27&#34; href=&#34;#__codelineno-2-27&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; ImportRouteTable1: !Equals [ &amp;quot;import&amp;quot;, !Select [ 0, !Split [ &amp;quot;:&amp;quot;, !Ref RouteTable1 ] ] ]&lt;a id=&#34;__codelineno-2-28&#34; name=&#34;__codelineno-2-28&#34; href=&#34;#__codelineno-2-28&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; ImportRouteTable2: !Equals [ &amp;quot;import&amp;quot;, !Select [ 0, !Split [ &amp;quot;:&amp;quot;, !Ref RouteTable2 ] ] ]&lt;a id=&#34;__codelineno-2-29&#34; name=&#34;__codelineno-2-29&#34; href=&#34;#__codelineno-2-29&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a id=&#34;__codelineno-2-30&#34; name=&#34;__codelineno-2-30&#34; href=&#34;#__codelineno-2-30&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Resources:&lt;a id=&#34;__codelineno-2-31&#34; name=&#34;__codelineno-2-31&#34; href=&#34;#__codelineno-2-31&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a id=&#34;__codelineno-2-32&#34; name=&#34;__codelineno-2-32&#34; href=&#34;#__codelineno-2-32&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; RouteTable1ToRemoteSubnet1:&lt;a id=&#34;__codelineno-2-33&#34; name=&#34;__codelineno-2-33&#34; href=&#34;#__codelineno-2-33&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; Type: AWS::EC2::Route&lt;a id=&#34;__codelineno-2-34&#34; name=&#34;__codelineno-2-34&#34; href=&#34;#__codelineno-2-34&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; Properties:&lt;a id=&#34;__codelineno-2-35&#34; name=&#34;__codelineno-2-35&#34; href=&#34;#__codelineno-2-35&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; DestinationCidrBlock: !If&lt;a id=&#34;__codelineno-2-36&#34; name=&#34;__codelineno-2-36&#34; href=&#34;#__codelineno-2-36&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; - ImportRemoteSubnet1CIDR&lt;a id=&#34;__codelineno-2-37&#34; name=&#34;__codelineno-2-37&#34; href=&#34;#__codelineno-2-37&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; - Fn::ImportValue: !Select [ 1, !Split [ &amp;quot;:&amp;quot;, !Ref RemoteSubnet1CIDR ] ] &lt;a id=&#34;__codelineno-2-38&#34; name=&#34;__codelineno-2-38&#34; href=&#34;#__codelineno-2-38&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; - !Ref &amp;#39;RemoteSubnet1CIDR&amp;#39;&lt;a id=&#34;__codelineno-2-39&#34; name=&#34;__codelineno-2-39&#34; href=&#34;#__codelineno-2-39&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; RouteTableId: !If&lt;a id=&#34;__codelineno-2-40&#34; name=&#34;__codelineno-2-40&#34; href=&#34;#__codelineno-2-40&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; - ImportRouteTable1&lt;a id=&#34;__codelineno-2-41&#34; name=&#34;__codelineno-2-41&#34; href=&#34;#__codelineno-2-41&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; - Fn::ImportValue: !Select [ 1, !Split [ &amp;quot;:&amp;quot;, !Ref RouteTable1 ] ] &lt;a id=&#34;__codelineno-2-42&#34; name=&#34;__codelineno-2-42&#34; href=&#34;#__codelineno-2-42&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; - !Ref &amp;#39;RouteTable1&amp;#39;&lt;a id=&#34;__codelineno-2-43&#34; name=&#34;__codelineno-2-43&#34; href=&#34;#__codelineno-2-43&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; VpcPeeringConnectionId: !Ref &amp;#39;VpcPeeringConnection&amp;#39;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;h3 id=&#34;conclusion&#34;&gt;Conclusion&lt;a class=&#34;headerlink&#34; href=&#34;#conclusion&#34; title=&#34;Permanent link&#34;&gt;&amp;para;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;I like this pattern because it:- makes it easier to create and read parameter files- doesn&#39;t have any external dependancies- also supports specifying resource ids as strings&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Feedback welcome in the comments.&lt;/p&gt;</description><link>https://mike.bailey.net.au/blog/2018/11/03/semantic-cloudformation-parameter-values/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=feed-syndication</link> <pubDate>Sun, 23 Feb 2025 09:08:55 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://mike.bailey.net.au/feed_rss_created.xml">mbailey/notes</source><comments>https://mike.bailey.net.au/blog/2018/11/03/semantic-cloudformation-parameter-values/#__comments</comments><guid isPermaLink="true">https://mike.bailey.net.au/blog/2018/11/03/semantic-cloudformation-parameter-values/</guid> </item> <item> <title>Don&#39;t Buck the System, Change it</title> <category>systems</category> <description>&lt;p&gt;I don&#39;t consider myself a Buddhist but attest to their belief that &#34;Life isSuffering&#34;. Not all of it all the time, but there&#39;s always some waiting. To somethis might sound like a pretty negative view but it doesn&#39;t have to be. Whatgives me strength is the knowledge that not &lt;em&gt;all&lt;/em&gt; suffering is out of mycontrol.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;This post is about making changes to systems that affect other people. It&#39;s notintended to cover changes to personal habits.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2 id=&#34;find-things-worth-suffering-for&#34;&gt;Find Things Worth Suffering For&lt;a class=&#34;headerlink&#34; href=&#34;#find-things-worth-suffering-for&#34; title=&#34;Permanent link&#34;&gt;&amp;para;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Life is change and change often involves suffering.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Bringing a pet into your life generally means accepting the grief the comes withoutliving them (unless you choose a &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/White_cockatoo&#34;&gt;White Cockatoo&lt;/a&gt; which can live 40-60years in captivity).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Improving you health, wealth or education might involve going without things youenjoy and doing things you don&#39;t.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;System change that affects other people, whether in the workplace, government orcommunity is hard work and success is never guaranteed. If you&#39;re going toattempt it, make sure you choose something worth suffering for.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2 id=&#34;serenity-courage-wisdom&#34;&gt;Serenity, Courage, Wisdom&lt;a class=&#34;headerlink&#34; href=&#34;#serenity-courage-wisdom&#34; title=&#34;Permanent link&#34;&gt;&amp;para;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Before the Internet came along, memes thrived in the form of kitchen calendarsand fridge magnets. You may be familiar with this one:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;Serenity Fridge Magnet&#34; src=&#34;../../../../images/serenity.png&#34; /&gt; &lt;em&gt;Serenity Fridge Magnet&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;God, grant me the serenity to accept the things I cannot change,&lt;br /&gt;Courage to change the things I can,&lt;br /&gt;And wisdom to know the difference.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Serenity_Prayer&#34;&gt;Reinhold Niebuh&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;Now I know Christian Theologians may not be in vogue these days but they &lt;em&gt;were&lt;/em&gt;&#34;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=iHmLljk2t8M&#34;&gt;putting a bird on it&lt;/a&gt;&#34; long before the hipsters caught ontoit. The value is in the message, not who said it.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2 id=&#34;accept-the-things-i-cannot-change&#34;&gt;&#34;Accept the Things I Cannot Change&#34;&lt;a class=&#34;headerlink&#34; href=&#34;#accept-the-things-i-cannot-change&#34; title=&#34;Permanent link&#34;&gt;&amp;para;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;I would change this to &#34;Accept the things I &lt;em&gt;should&lt;/em&gt; not change&#34;:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;A sysadmin with root privileges &lt;em&gt;can&lt;/em&gt; invade people&#39;s privacy&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;A person in executive government &lt;em&gt;can&lt;/em&gt; enact laws that cause unnecessary suffering&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;Just because you &lt;em&gt;can&lt;/em&gt; change the world to better suit you, it doesn&#39;t followthat you &lt;em&gt;should&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I accept that I cannot change all the fridge magnets. It&#39;s reckon I &lt;em&gt;could&lt;/em&gt; getAlcoholics Anonymous to change the version they promote but &lt;em&gt;shouldn&#39;t&lt;/em&gt; becausethe change:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;would provide little benefit to me&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;would provide little benefit to others&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;would require a huge amount of effort (including other people&#39;s)&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;maybe do it&#34; src=&#34;../../../../images/maybe-do-it.jpg&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2 id=&#34;do-you-have-skin-in-the-game&#34;&gt;Do you have &#39;skin in the game&#39;?&lt;a class=&#34;headerlink&#34; href=&#34;#do-you-have-skin-in-the-game&#34; title=&#34;Permanent link&#34;&gt;&amp;para;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Just because something &lt;em&gt;should&lt;/em&gt; change, that doesn&#39;t neccessarily mean youshould be the one to do it. You know best how to scratch your own itch. Avoidtrying to lead on change that doesn&#39;t impact on your personally. You&#39;re unlikelyto have the passion, connection and understanding of someone with skin in thegame. By all means, support these efforts where you believe in the goals butdon&#39;t try to own them.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;A Pig and a Chicken are walking down the road.&lt;br /&gt;The Chicken says: &#34;Hey Pig, I was thinking we should open a restaurant!&#34;&lt;br /&gt;Pig replies: &#34;Hm, maybe, what would we call it?&#34;&lt;br /&gt;The Chicken responds: &#34;How about &#39;ham-n-eggs&#39;?&#34;&lt;br /&gt;The Pig thinks for a moment and says: &#34;No thanks. I&#39;d be committed, but you&#39;donly be involved.&#34;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Reinhold_Niebuhr&#34;&gt;Pig and Chicken fable&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;It&#39;s captured more succintly in the &#34;&lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Nothing_About_Us_Without_Us&#34;&gt;Nothing About Us WithoutUs&lt;/a&gt;&#34; mantra popular with ethnic, disability and othermarginalise groups.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2 id=&#34;does-anyone-else-knowcare&#34;&gt;Does anyone else know/care?&lt;a class=&#34;headerlink&#34; href=&#34;#does-anyone-else-knowcare&#34; title=&#34;Permanent link&#34;&gt;&amp;para;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Who else would benefit from the change? Who would suffer? If there isn&#39;t thelikelihood of a net benefit to the group, you&#39;re unlikely to get the buy-inrequired to make the change. Unless you intend to mislead or coerce people intodoing things your way, you&#39;re probably best accepting this as a thing youshouldn&#39;t change.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2 id=&#34;courage-to-change-the-things-i-can&#34;&gt;&#34;Courage to Change the Things I Can&#34;&lt;a class=&#34;headerlink&#34; href=&#34;#courage-to-change-the-things-i-can&#34; title=&#34;Permanent link&#34;&gt;&amp;para;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;I don&#39;t think most people realise how malleable the world is. The video belowsays it better than I can.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;iframe width=&#34;560&#34; height=&#34;315&#34; src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/zklbZR9025Y&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34; allow=&#34;accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture&#34; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;“When you grow up you tend to get told that the world is the way it is andyour life is just to live your life inside the world. Try not to bash into thewalls too much. Try to have a nice family life, have fun, save a little money.That&#39;s a very limited life. Life can be much broader once you discover onesimple fact: Everything around you that you call life was made up by peoplethat were no smarter than you. And you can change it, you can influence it…Once you learn that, you&#39;ll never be the same again.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Steve Jobs&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;h2 id=&#34;and-the-wisdom-to-know-the-difference&#34;&gt;&#34;And the Wisdom to Know the Difference&#34;&lt;a class=&#34;headerlink&#34; href=&#34;#and-the-wisdom-to-know-the-difference&#34; title=&#34;Permanent link&#34;&gt;&amp;para;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;I&#39;m not sure about wisdom but I hope this post offers some food for thought.&lt;/p&gt;</description><link>https://mike.bailey.net.au/blog/2018/11/04/dont-buck-the-system-change-it/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=feed-syndication</link> <pubDate>Sun, 23 Feb 2025 09:08:55 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://mike.bailey.net.au/feed_rss_created.xml">mbailey/notes</source><comments>https://mike.bailey.net.au/blog/2018/11/04/dont-buck-the-system-change-it/#__comments</comments><guid isPermaLink="true">https://mike.bailey.net.au/blog/2018/11/04/dont-buck-the-system-change-it/</guid> </item> <item> <title>Why You Should Enable S3 Block Public Access</title> <category>aws</category> <category>s3</category> <category>systems</category> <description>&lt;p&gt;Amazon S3 enables you to accidentally share confidential information with the world.The potential impact of misconfiguration justifies implementing controls made availableby AWS in November 2018.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Numerous &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/nagwww/s3-leaks&#34;&gt;data breaches&lt;/a&gt; due to misconfigured AWS Buckets have beenreported in recent times and &lt;a href=&#34;https://medium.com/@grayhatwarfare/how-to-search-for-open-amazon-s3-buckets-and-their-contents-https-buckets-grayhatwarfare-com-577b7b437e01&#34;&gt;free tools&lt;/a&gt; have been released thatcan be used to scan for them. Even AWS staff have &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.zdnet.com/article/aws-error-exposed-godaddy-server-secrets/?ref&#34;&gt;made their buckets world readableby mistake&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.aws.amazon.com/AmazonS3/latest/dev/access-control-block-public-access.html&#34;&gt;S3 Block Public Access&lt;/a&gt; allows you to prevent configuration of S3 Buckets and the objectswithin them from being accessible to the whole world.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;It still allows you to share objects with specified targets such as:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;AWS Services&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;other AWS Accounts&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;specified IP address ranges&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;h2 id=&#34;how-we-got-here&#34;&gt;How we got here&lt;a class=&#34;headerlink&#34; href=&#34;#how-we-got-here&#34; title=&#34;Permanent link&#34;&gt;&amp;para;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Amazon S3 was the first AWS Service launched, way back in 2006. Users storefile objects in Buckets and can control access to them through a variety ofmechanisms, including:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Bucket ACLs&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Object ACLs&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Bucket Policies&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;IAM Polcies&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;Objects can be made accessable via:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Unauthenticated Web requests (via http/https)&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;AWS API calls (via AWS Web Console, AWSCLI, SDKs, etc)&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.aws.amazon.com/AmazonS3/latest/dev/S3Torrent.html&#34;&gt;BitTorrent&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;Confusion around the different methods for controlling access can lead tomistakes. Amazon&#39;s &#34;&lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.aws.amazon.com/AmazonS3/latest/dev/access-policy-alternatives-guidelines.html&#34;&gt;only recommended use case&lt;/a&gt; for the bucketACL is to grant write permission to the Amazon S3 Log Delivery group to writeaccess log objects to your bucket, yet Bucket ACLs still make it easy to makethe Bucket world readable (and even writable!).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2 id=&#34;detecting-publicly-accessible-buckets&#34;&gt;Detecting Publicly Accessible Buckets&lt;a class=&#34;headerlink&#34; href=&#34;#detecting-publicly-accessible-buckets&#34; title=&#34;Permanent link&#34;&gt;&amp;para;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;AWS Trusted Advisor&#39;s &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.amazonaws.cn/en/support/trustedadvisor/best-practices/&#34;&gt;S3 Bucket Permissions Check&lt;/a&gt; has been free since Feb 2018.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Business and Enterprise support customers can use these checks to enableautomated actions via Trusted Advisor&#39;s &lt;a href=&#34;http://docs.aws.amazon.com/awssupport/latest/user/cloudwatch-events-ta.html&#34;&gt;integration with CloudWatch Events&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2 id=&#34;block-s3-public-access&#34;&gt;Block S3 Public Access&lt;a class=&#34;headerlink&#34; href=&#34;#block-s3-public-access&#34; title=&#34;Permanent link&#34;&gt;&amp;para;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;In Nov 2018, AWS launched a new feature that allows you to control againstObjects in S3 Buckets being made Public. It consists of four settings which canbe applied at the Bucket or Account level. Applying at a Bucket level may enablethe rules to be overridden.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Objects intended to be shared publicly (e.g. static websites) can have a BucketPolicy with configured to grant read access to a CloudFront &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.aws.amazon.com/AmazonCloudFront/latest/DeveloperGuide/private-content-restricting-access-to-s3.html#private-content-granting-permissions-to-oai&#34;&gt;Origin Access Identity&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;For situations where CloudFront is considered overkill (it can take ~30 minutes to provision),users may consider granting access to a specific IP Range, AWS Account or IAM Role.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3 id=&#34;what-does-public-mean&#34;&gt;What does &lt;code&gt;Public&lt;/code&gt; mean&lt;a class=&#34;headerlink&#34; href=&#34;#what-does-public-mean&#34; title=&#34;Permanent link&#34;&gt;&amp;para;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;ACLs: AllUsers or AuthenticatedUsers&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Policies&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;In order to be considered non-public, a bucket policy must grant access only to fixed values (values that don&#39;t contain a wildcard) of one or more of the following:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;A set of Classless Inter-Domain Routings (CIDRs), using aws:SourceIp. For more information about CIDR, see RFC 4632 on the RFC Editor website.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;An AWS principal, user, role, or service principal&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;aws:SourceArn&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;aws:SourceVpc&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;aws:SourceVpce&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;aws:SourceOwner&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;aws:SourceAccount&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;s3:x-amz-server-side-encryption-aws-kms-key-id&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;aws:userid, outside the pattern &#34;AROLEID:*&#34;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;h2 id=&#34;enabling-s3-block-public-access-on-an-account&#34;&gt;Enabling S3 Block Public Access on an Account&lt;a class=&#34;headerlink&#34; href=&#34;#enabling-s3-block-public-access-on-an-account&#34; title=&#34;Permanent link&#34;&gt;&amp;para;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Applying S3 Block Public Access may break things! Administrators applying thisfeature should familiarize themselves with the &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.aws.amazon.com/AmazonS3/latest/dev/access-control-block-public-access.html&#34;&gt;AWS Documentation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In order to perform Block Public Access operations on an account, use the AWSCLI service s3control.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The four settings that can be configured independantly) are:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;BlockPublicAcls&lt;/strong&gt;: Block setting of ACLs if they include public access&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;IgnorePublicAcls&lt;/strong&gt;: Ignore Public ACLs&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;BlockPublicPolicy&lt;/strong&gt;: Block setting of Policy that includes public access&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;RestrictPublicBuckets&lt;/strong&gt;: Restrict buckets with public Policy to same account and AWS Principals&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;The account-level operations that use this service are:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;PUT PublicAccessBlock (for an account)&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;GET PublicAccessBlock (for an account)&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;DELETE PublicAccessBlock (for an account)&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;h2 id=&#34;example-cloudformation-for-granting-access-to-origin-access-identity-and-ip-range&#34;&gt;Example CloudFormation for granting access to Origin Access Identity and IP range&lt;a class=&#34;headerlink&#34; href=&#34;#example-cloudformation-for-granting-access-to-origin-access-identity-and-ip-range&#34; title=&#34;Permanent link&#34;&gt;&amp;para;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;code&gt;&lt;a id=&#34;__codelineno-0-1&#34; name=&#34;__codelineno-0-1&#34; href=&#34;#__codelineno-0-1&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; CFOAI:&lt;a id=&#34;__codelineno-0-2&#34; name=&#34;__codelineno-0-2&#34; href=&#34;#__codelineno-0-2&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; Type: AWS::CloudFront::CloudFrontOriginAccessIdentity&lt;a id=&#34;__codelineno-0-3&#34; name=&#34;__codelineno-0-3&#34; href=&#34;#__codelineno-0-3&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; Properties:&lt;a id=&#34;__codelineno-0-4&#34; name=&#34;__codelineno-0-4&#34; href=&#34;#__codelineno-0-4&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; CloudFrontOriginAccessIdentityConfig:&lt;a id=&#34;__codelineno-0-5&#34; name=&#34;__codelineno-0-5&#34; href=&#34;#__codelineno-0-5&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; Comment: !Ref AWS::StackName&lt;a id=&#34;__codelineno-0-6&#34; name=&#34;__codelineno-0-6&#34; href=&#34;#__codelineno-0-6&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a id=&#34;__codelineno-0-7&#34; name=&#34;__codelineno-0-7&#34; href=&#34;#__codelineno-0-7&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; Bucket:&lt;a id=&#34;__codelineno-0-8&#34; name=&#34;__codelineno-0-8&#34; href=&#34;#__codelineno-0-8&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; Type: AWS::S3::Bucket&lt;a id=&#34;__codelineno-0-9&#34; name=&#34;__codelineno-0-9&#34; href=&#34;#__codelineno-0-9&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a id=&#34;__codelineno-0-10&#34; name=&#34;__codelineno-0-10&#34; href=&#34;#__codelineno-0-10&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; BucketPolicy:&lt;a id=&#34;__codelineno-0-11&#34; name=&#34;__codelineno-0-11&#34; href=&#34;#__codelineno-0-11&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; Type: AWS::S3::BucketPolicy&lt;a id=&#34;__codelineno-0-12&#34; name=&#34;__codelineno-0-12&#34; href=&#34;#__codelineno-0-12&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; Properties:&lt;a id=&#34;__codelineno-0-13&#34; name=&#34;__codelineno-0-13&#34; href=&#34;#__codelineno-0-13&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; Bucket: !Ref Bucket&lt;a id=&#34;__codelineno-0-14&#34; name=&#34;__codelineno-0-14&#34; href=&#34;#__codelineno-0-14&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; PolicyDocument:&lt;a id=&#34;__codelineno-0-15&#34; name=&#34;__codelineno-0-15&#34; href=&#34;#__codelineno-0-15&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; Version: 2012-10-17&lt;a id=&#34;__codelineno-0-16&#34; name=&#34;__codelineno-0-16&#34; href=&#34;#__codelineno-0-16&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; Id: PolicyForCloudFrontPrivateContent&lt;a id=&#34;__codelineno-0-17&#34; name=&#34;__codelineno-0-17&#34; href=&#34;#__codelineno-0-17&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; Statement:&lt;a id=&#34;__codelineno-0-18&#34; name=&#34;__codelineno-0-18&#34; href=&#34;#__codelineno-0-18&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; - Sid: Grant a CloudFront Origin Identity access to support private content&lt;a id=&#34;__codelineno-0-19&#34; name=&#34;__codelineno-0-19&#34; href=&#34;#__codelineno-0-19&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; Action: &amp;quot;s3:GetObject&amp;quot;&lt;a id=&#34;__codelineno-0-20&#34; name=&#34;__codelineno-0-20&#34; href=&#34;#__codelineno-0-20&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; Effect: &amp;quot;Allow&amp;quot;&lt;a id=&#34;__codelineno-0-21&#34; name=&#34;__codelineno-0-21&#34; href=&#34;#__codelineno-0-21&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; Principal:&lt;a id=&#34;__codelineno-0-22&#34; name=&#34;__codelineno-0-22&#34; href=&#34;#__codelineno-0-22&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; CanonicalUser: !GetAtt CFOAI.S3CanonicalUserId&lt;a id=&#34;__codelineno-0-23&#34; name=&#34;__codelineno-0-23&#34; href=&#34;#__codelineno-0-23&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; Resource: !Sub &amp;quot;arn:aws:s3:::${Bucket}/*&amp;quot;&lt;a id=&#34;__codelineno-0-24&#34; name=&#34;__codelineno-0-24&#34; href=&#34;#__codelineno-0-24&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; - Sid: Grant access from Trusted Network&lt;a id=&#34;__codelineno-0-25&#34; name=&#34;__codelineno-0-25&#34; href=&#34;#__codelineno-0-25&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; Action: &amp;quot;s3:GetObject&amp;quot;&lt;a id=&#34;__codelineno-0-26&#34; name=&#34;__codelineno-0-26&#34; href=&#34;#__codelineno-0-26&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; Effect: &amp;quot;Allow&amp;quot;&lt;a id=&#34;__codelineno-0-27&#34; name=&#34;__codelineno-0-27&#34; href=&#34;#__codelineno-0-27&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; Principal: &amp;quot;*&amp;quot;&lt;a id=&#34;__codelineno-0-28&#34; name=&#34;__codelineno-0-28&#34; href=&#34;#__codelineno-0-28&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; Resource: !Sub &amp;quot;arn:aws:s3:::${Bucket}/*&amp;quot;&lt;a id=&#34;__codelineno-0-29&#34; name=&#34;__codelineno-0-29&#34; href=&#34;#__codelineno-0-29&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; Condition:&lt;a id=&#34;__codelineno-0-30&#34; name=&#34;__codelineno-0-30&#34; href=&#34;#__codelineno-0-30&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; IpAddress:&lt;a id=&#34;__codelineno-0-31&#34; name=&#34;__codelineno-0-31&#34; href=&#34;#__codelineno-0-31&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; aws:SourceIp: !Ref OfficeIp&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><link>https://mike.bailey.net.au/blog/2019/03/05/why-you-should-enable-s3-block-public-access/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=feed-syndication</link> <pubDate>Sun, 23 Feb 2025 09:08:55 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://mike.bailey.net.au/feed_rss_created.xml">mbailey/notes</source><comments>https://mike.bailey.net.au/blog/2019/03/05/why-you-should-enable-s3-block-public-access/#__comments</comments><guid isPermaLink="true">https://mike.bailey.net.au/blog/2019/03/05/why-you-should-enable-s3-block-public-access/</guid> </item> <item> <title>Right-sizing your AWS Lambdas</title> <category>aws</category> <category>s3</category> <category>systems</category> <description>&lt;p&gt;I was recently able to reduce the cost of one of our serverless applicationsby more than half by reducing the memory allocated to the lambdas.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Possible reasons we didn&#39;t do this earlier:- initial cost was low but increased later as traffic increased- team didn&#39;t have knowledge/confidence to set lower threshold- we weren&#39;t monitoring/alerting on memory usage&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2 id=&#34;aws-lambda-pricing&#34;&gt;AWS Lambda Pricing&lt;a class=&#34;headerlink&#34; href=&#34;#aws-lambda-pricing&#34; title=&#34;Permanent link&#34;&gt;&amp;para;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;AWS Lambda lets you run code without provisioning or managing servers. You pay only for the compute time you consume - there is no charge when your code is not running.- https://aws.amazon.com/lambda/&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;Lambda is charged based on number and duration of requests (&lt;a href=&#34;https://aws.amazon.com/lambda/pricing/&#34;&gt;AWSPricing&lt;/a&gt;). Duration is measured in GB-seconds which is why it&#39;spossible to reduce your cost by reducing the maximum memory provided to youlambdas.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;You specify an amount between 128 MB and 3,008 MB in 64 MB increments. Lambdaallocates CPU power linearly in proportion to the amount of memory configured.At 1,792 MB, a function has the equivalent of 1 full vCPU (one vCPU-second ofcredits per second).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;There are situations where provisioning far more memory than will be used is agood choice. If the function is CPU bound (as opposed to waiting on responsesfrom the network) then increasing CPU will reduce duration, improvingperformance without negatively impacting on cost.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The risk when setting memory for a Lambda is that execution halts immediatelyif the function runs out of memory. Changes to the function over time may alterit&#39;s memory usage so we&#39;re best to monitor and alert on this.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2 id=&#34;checking-memory-usage&#34;&gt;Checking Memory Usage&lt;a class=&#34;headerlink&#34; href=&#34;#checking-memory-usage&#34; title=&#34;Permanent link&#34;&gt;&amp;para;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;It&#39;s relatively simple to report on the maximum memory being used bya lambda. This can help you select an appropriate amount.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Lambda logs &lt;code&gt;maxMemoryUsed&lt;/code&gt; for each function invocation to CloudWatch Logs.CloudWatch Logs Insights includes a sample query that reports on overprovisionedmemory.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The example below is for a function that spends most of it&#39;s time waitingon responses from web apis. The report shows it had 976 MB memory and usedat most 275 MB in the past three days. Note that the sample query returnsfigures that may be confusing due to them using a different unit (MiB) than isused for configuring Lambda functions (MB). (I&#39;ve requested this be fixed).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;CloudWatch Logs Insights query displaying overprovisioned memory in Lambda&#34; src=&#34;../../../../images/cloudwatch-logs-insights-lambda-overprovisioned.png&#34; /&gt;&lt;em&gt;CloudWatch Logs Insights query displaying overprovisioned memory in Lambda&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2 id=&#34;choose-good-memory-limit-for-your-function&#34;&gt;Choose good memory limit for your function&lt;a class=&#34;headerlink&#34; href=&#34;#choose-good-memory-limit-for-your-function&#34; title=&#34;Permanent link&#34;&gt;&amp;para;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;We initially decided to set the memory to 384 MB and setup an alarm to alert usif a function uses 80% of that (307 MB). On checking CloudWatch later we sawfunction duration increased after the memory was decreased. This was due to theCPU decrease that happens when you reduce memory for the lambda. We decided tomanually increase and decrease memory until we found a sweet spot of 512 MB.This was still a 50% decrease in cost with minimal impact on duration.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2 id=&#34;monitor-and-alert-in-case-things-change&#34;&gt;Monitor and alert in case things change&lt;a class=&#34;headerlink&#34; href=&#34;#monitor-and-alert-in-case-things-change&#34; title=&#34;Permanent link&#34;&gt;&amp;para;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;If our lambda memory usage increases over time, we want to be notified.Below are snippets from the CloudFormation template for our applicationthat write memory used to a custom CloudWatch Metric and alert us if itgets to 80% of the maximum we have set.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3 id=&#34;cloudwatch-logs-metric-filter&#34;&gt;CloudWatch Logs Metric Filter&lt;a class=&#34;headerlink&#34; href=&#34;#cloudwatch-logs-metric-filter&#34; title=&#34;Permanent link&#34;&gt;&amp;para;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;A Metrics Filter parses all logs from the function and writes the&lt;code&gt;max_memory_used&lt;/code&gt; value to a custom metric. This provides a convenientway to graph and alert on that metric.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;code&gt;&lt;a id=&#34;__codelineno-0-1&#34; name=&#34;__codelineno-0-1&#34; href=&#34;#__codelineno-0-1&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;AppMetricFilter:&lt;a id=&#34;__codelineno-0-2&#34; name=&#34;__codelineno-0-2&#34; href=&#34;#__codelineno-0-2&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; Type: AWS::Logs::MetricFilter&lt;a id=&#34;__codelineno-0-3&#34; name=&#34;__codelineno-0-3&#34; href=&#34;#__codelineno-0-3&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; Properties:&lt;a id=&#34;__codelineno-0-4&#34; name=&#34;__codelineno-0-4&#34; href=&#34;#__codelineno-0-4&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; LogGroupName:&lt;a id=&#34;__codelineno-0-5&#34; name=&#34;__codelineno-0-5&#34; href=&#34;#__codelineno-0-5&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; Ref: AppDashserverLogGroup&lt;a id=&#34;__codelineno-0-6&#34; name=&#34;__codelineno-0-6&#34; href=&#34;#__codelineno-0-6&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; FilterPattern: &amp;#39;[ report_label=&amp;quot;REPORT&amp;quot;, ..., label=&amp;quot;Used:&amp;quot;, max_memory_used_value, unit=&amp;quot;MB&amp;quot; ]&amp;#39;&lt;a id=&#34;__codelineno-0-7&#34; name=&#34;__codelineno-0-7&#34; href=&#34;#__codelineno-0-7&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; MetricTransformations:&lt;a id=&#34;__codelineno-0-8&#34; name=&#34;__codelineno-0-8&#34; href=&#34;#__codelineno-0-8&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; - MetricValue: &amp;#39;$max_memory_used_value&amp;#39;&lt;a id=&#34;__codelineno-0-9&#34; name=&#34;__codelineno-0-9&#34; href=&#34;#__codelineno-0-9&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; MetricNamespace: LogMetrics/Lambda&lt;a id=&#34;__codelineno-0-10&#34; name=&#34;__codelineno-0-10&#34; href=&#34;#__codelineno-0-10&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; MetricName: example-app-memoryUsed&amp;#39;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;I&#39;d not come across Metrics Filters before but am glad I have. FromwhatI can gather, a custom metric costs you $0.30/month but there is noadditional charge to have your CloudWatch logs filtered through aMetrics Filter to feed it.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3 id=&#34;cloudwatch-alarm&#34;&gt;CloudWatch Alarm&lt;a class=&#34;headerlink&#34; href=&#34;#cloudwatch-alarm&#34; title=&#34;Permanent link&#34;&gt;&amp;para;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;We created a CloudWatch alarm to notify us if the maximum memory used bya function exceeded 80% of what it was provisioned with.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;code&gt;&lt;a id=&#34;__codelineno-1-1&#34; name=&#34;__codelineno-1-1&#34; href=&#34;#__codelineno-1-1&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;AppAlarmLambdaMemory:&lt;a id=&#34;__codelineno-1-2&#34; name=&#34;__codelineno-1-2&#34; href=&#34;#__codelineno-1-2&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; Type: AWS::CloudWatch::Alarm&lt;a id=&#34;__codelineno-1-3&#34; name=&#34;__codelineno-1-3&#34; href=&#34;#__codelineno-1-3&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; Properties:&lt;a id=&#34;__codelineno-1-4&#34; name=&#34;__codelineno-1-4&#34; href=&#34;#__codelineno-1-4&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; AlarmActions:&lt;a id=&#34;__codelineno-1-5&#34; name=&#34;__codelineno-1-5&#34; href=&#34;#__codelineno-1-5&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; - Ref: AwsAlertsAlarm&lt;a id=&#34;__codelineno-1-6&#34; name=&#34;__codelineno-1-6&#34; href=&#34;#__codelineno-1-6&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; AlarmDescription: Lambda memory usage above 80% for example-app-memoryUsed&lt;a id=&#34;__codelineno-1-7&#34; name=&#34;__codelineno-1-7&#34; href=&#34;#__codelineno-1-7&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; ComparisonOperator: GreaterThanThreshold&lt;a id=&#34;__codelineno-1-8&#34; name=&#34;__codelineno-1-8&#34; href=&#34;#__codelineno-1-8&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; EvaluationPeriods: 1&lt;a id=&#34;__codelineno-1-9&#34; name=&#34;__codelineno-1-9&#34; href=&#34;#__codelineno-1-9&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; MetricName: &amp;#39;example-app-memoryUsed&amp;#39;&lt;a id=&#34;__codelineno-1-10&#34; name=&#34;__codelineno-1-10&#34; href=&#34;#__codelineno-1-10&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; Namespace: LogMetrics/Lambda&lt;a id=&#34;__codelineno-1-11&#34; name=&#34;__codelineno-1-11&#34; href=&#34;#__codelineno-1-11&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; Period: 60&lt;a id=&#34;__codelineno-1-12&#34; name=&#34;__codelineno-1-12&#34; href=&#34;#__codelineno-1-12&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; Statistic: Maximum&lt;a id=&#34;__codelineno-1-13&#34; name=&#34;__codelineno-1-13&#34; href=&#34;#__codelineno-1-13&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; Threshold: 307 # 80% of provisioned memory&lt;a id=&#34;__codelineno-1-14&#34; name=&#34;__codelineno-1-14&#34; href=&#34;#__codelineno-1-14&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; Unit: Megabytes&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;h2 id=&#34;checking-your-lambdas-cost&#34;&gt;Checking your lambda&#39;s cost&lt;a class=&#34;headerlink&#34; href=&#34;#checking-your-lambdas-cost&#34; title=&#34;Permanent link&#34;&gt;&amp;para;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;I recommend using AWS Cost Explorer to view at your lambda costs. I generallyaccess it via the AWS Console although I was excited to discover you can alsoquery it via AWSCLI).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Some hints to help you breakdown costs by Lambda:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Filters -&amp;gt; Include Only -&amp;gt; Lambda&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Group By -&amp;gt; Tag: aws:cloudformation:stack-name&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;h2 id=&#34;reduced-waste-and-early-warning-against-failure&#34;&gt;Reduced waste and early warning against failure&lt;a class=&#34;headerlink&#34; href=&#34;#reduced-waste-and-early-warning-against-failure&#34; title=&#34;Permanent link&#34;&gt;&amp;para;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;This work will save us around $600/month running this application. It alsoprovides us with more visibility into memory usage and alerts for when itincreases.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;It&#39;s often a tough call to decide whether ROI on cost savings will justify theeffort. You don&#39;t know till try it. If you&#39;ve blown your budget that can be amotivation. Hopefully the information here can help others in their efforts toreduce waste.&lt;/p&gt;</description><link>https://mike.bailey.net.au/blog/2019/05/09/right-sizing-your-aws-lambdas/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=feed-syndication</link> <pubDate>Sun, 23 Feb 2025 09:08:55 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://mike.bailey.net.au/feed_rss_created.xml">mbailey/notes</source><comments>https://mike.bailey.net.au/blog/2019/05/09/right-sizing-your-aws-lambdas/#__comments</comments><guid isPermaLink="true">https://mike.bailey.net.au/blog/2019/05/09/right-sizing-your-aws-lambdas/</guid> </item> <item> <title>Fixed! ~~Melburnians Misinformed about Lockdown Rules for Exercise~~</title> <author>mbailey</author> <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Update: July 17 2020&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Victorian Govt has updated restrictions to say you cannot travel further than necessary for exercise.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.dhhs.vic.gov.au/sites/default/files/documents/202007/Stay%20at%20Home%20%28Restricted%20Areas%29%20%28No%202%29%28signed%2010%20July%29.pdf&#34;&gt;Stay at Home Directions (Restricted Areas) (No2)&lt;/a&gt; was released on 10 July 2020.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;(1A) A person may only leave their premises under subclause(1) where it does not involve unreasonable travel or travelling to a place for an unreasonable amount of time.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Note 2: unreasonable travel would include travel within the Restricted Area to exercise or outdoor recreation where that type of activity can be done closer to home. Travelling to an area outside the Restricted Area for exercise or outdoor recreation is prohibitied under these directions&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;hr /&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Update: July 9 2020&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I was pleased to receive a response informing me that &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.vic.gov.au/coronavirus-covid-19-restrictions-victoria#a-return-to-stay-at-home-restrictions-for-metropolitan-melbourne-and-mitchell-shire-from-1159pm-on-wednesday-8-july-2020&#34;&gt;www.vic.gov.au&lt;/a&gt; has been updated to remove the ambiguity.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;It&#39;s great that this was addressed so promptly in what I&#39;m sure is a very busytime for the people involved.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr /&gt;&lt;p&gt;A page on the Victorian Government&#39;s website has led many to believe they cannot leave their Local Government Area (LGA) for exercise.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;Additionally, there will only be 3 reasons to cross the border of these metropolitan areas:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Shopping for food and supplies Medical care and caregiving Study and work – if you can’t do it from home&#34;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.vic.gov.au/coronavirus-covid-19-restrictions-victoria#a-return-to-stay-at-home-restrictions-for-metropolitan-melbourne-and-mitchell-shire-from-1159pm-on-wednesday-8-july-2020&#34;&gt;www.vic.gov.au&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;This is in contrast to advice on the Department of Health and Social Services(DHSS) website which makes clear the new Stay At Home restrictions preventpeople leaving Greater Melbourne for exercise, but not their LGA.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;I live in Melbourne - can I exercise outside with someone who is not part of my household?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;From 11:59pm on 8 July, changed gathering limits apply to the Melbournemetropolitan area and the Shire of Mitchell. If you live in this area, you areonly allowed to exercise outside with one other person, or members of yourhousehold.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In order to help stop the spread of coronavirus (COVID-19) across the state,you cannot leave metropolitan Melbourne or Mitchell Shire to exercise.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;While exercising outside you should keep 1.5 metres distance between yourselfand others and avoid sharing equipment.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.dhhs.vic.gov.au/updated-restrictions-1159pm-wednesday-8-july&#34;&gt;www.dhhs.vic.gov.au&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;Further down the page the DHSS makes clear you can leave your LGA as long asyou don&#39;t leave the Melbourne metro area:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;I live in Melbourne. Can I visit the beach?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Yes. As long as it is for the purpose of exercise and within the Melbournemetropolitan area. You are only allowed to exercise outside with one otherperson, or members of your household.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;While exercising outside you should keep 1.5 metres distance between yourselfand others and avoid sharing equipment.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In order to help stop the spread of coronavirus (COVID-19) across the state,you cannot leave metropolitan Melbourne or the Shire of Mitchell toexercise.&#34;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.dhhs.vic.gov.au/updated-restrictions-1159pm-wednesday-8-july&#34;&gt;www.dhhs.vic.gov.au&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;This is an important distinction for many Melburnians but particularly forthose &lt;strong&gt;living alone without family/friends in their LGA&lt;/strong&gt;. Six weekswithout seeing a friend or loved one in person could seriously exacerbate analready challenging time in isolation.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I&#39;ve already spoken with a couple of people who are convinced they cannot leavetheir LGA for exercise based on the wording on www.vic.gov.au. I&#39;m convinced thatthere has been a misunderstanding and that DHSS is the more credible source inthis instance.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I&#39;ve submitted a request through&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.vic.gov.au/contact-us&#34;&gt;https://www.vic.gov.au/contact-us&lt;/a&gt; to askthat they update the wording on their page to make clear that we are notprevented from crossing LGA boundaries for exercise within Melbourne Metroarea.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The public deserve clarity on the Stay at Home restrictions being applied tothem. Every effort should be made by government to ensure information providedis correct and able to be understood. If and when mistakes are detected, theyshould be corrected promptly because misinformation spreads like a virus.&lt;/p&gt;</description><link>https://mike.bailey.net.au/blog/2020/07/08/fixed-melburnians-misinformed-about-lockdown-rules-for-exercise/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=feed-syndication</link> <pubDate>Sun, 23 Feb 2025 09:08:55 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://mike.bailey.net.au/feed_rss_created.xml">mbailey/notes</source><comments>https://mike.bailey.net.au/blog/2020/07/08/fixed-melburnians-misinformed-about-lockdown-rules-for-exercise/#__comments</comments><guid isPermaLink="true">https://mike.bailey.net.au/blog/2020/07/08/fixed-melburnians-misinformed-about-lockdown-rules-for-exercise/</guid> </item> <item> <title>Fun with Retinal Burns</title> <author>mbailey</author> <category>perception</category> <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Disclaimer: Don&#39;t look at any bright light source. It may damage your eyes!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The sound of a fly buzzing meant  one more thing for me to before going to bed.What happened next took me by surprise and provided some fascinatingentertainment that I thought I&#39;d share with you.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Returning from the kitchen with a can of fly spray, I heard it&#39;s intendedtarget was in the last remaining light source in my house - the big orangelampshade by the couch. After peering down into the lampshade and releasing acouple of light sprays I returned to the darkened kitchen only to notice I wasseeing spots, three large overlapping ones to be precise.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;These black Venn Diagrammesque apparitions were due to photobleaching of thechemicals my eyes use to sense light. They were in three distinct placesbecause the eye flicks quickly when scanning - if I had been watching a marblerace I&#39;m sure it would have been a circle.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Anyway, we&#39;ve all see spots right? What was really neat was what I discoverednext...&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Covering my eye made the spots go a light colour. Looking at the pantry doorsresulting in them being dark. The spots faded within seconds however coveringmy eyes brought them back, as did shifting my gaze to a different area in theroom. I think I&#39;ve found a new way to demonstrate perceptual filling-in. Untilnow I&#39;ve only heard of &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.med.yale.edu/neurobio/mccormick/fill_in_seminar/introduction.html&#34;&gt;blind spotfill-in&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The beauty of retinal burn fill-in is that you don&#39;t need to find your blindspot, or be a certain distance from things as you can control where you placethe burn. It&#39;s amazing to watch the burn dissolve as the brain fills in themissing information. I&#39;d advise against deliberately looking into any brightlight source &lt;strong&gt;but&lt;/strong&gt; next time it happens I suggest you use the opportunity toexperience first hand the difference between the signals your eyes send andwhat you perceive.&lt;/p&gt;</description><link>https://mike.bailey.net.au/blog/2012/11/26/fun-with-retinal-burns/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=feed-syndication</link> <pubDate>Mon, 26 Nov 2012 12:32:11 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://mike.bailey.net.au/feed_rss_created.xml">mbailey/notes</source><comments>https://mike.bailey.net.au/blog/2012/11/26/fun-with-retinal-burns/#__comments</comments><guid isPermaLink="true">https://mike.bailey.net.au/blog/2012/11/26/fun-with-retinal-burns/</guid> </item> <item> <title>Vagrant notes</title> <author>mbailey</author> <category>vagrant</category> <category>virtualization</category> <description>&lt;p&gt;I&#39;m a massive fan of &lt;a href=&#34;http://vagrantup.com/&#34;&gt;Vagrant&lt;/a&gt;&#39;s command linevirtualisation goodness. This post is me trying to find a public place for myvagrant notes to rest (I couldn&#39;t find a cardboard box).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3 id=&#34;vagrant-hostmaster&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/mosaicxm/vagrant-hostmaster&#34;&gt;vagrant-hostmaster&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;headerlink&#34; href=&#34;#vagrant-hostmaster&#34; title=&#34;Permanent link&#34;&gt;&amp;para;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;This vagrant rubygem plugin automatically updates /etc/hosts on your guests andhost box each time you run vagrant [up|provision]&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3 id=&#34;vagrant-vbguest&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/dotless-de/vagrant-vbguest&#34;&gt;vagrant-vbguest&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;headerlink&#34; href=&#34;#vagrant-vbguest&#34; title=&#34;Permanent link&#34;&gt;&amp;para;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;vagrant-vbguest&lt;/em&gt; is a &lt;a href=&#34;http://vagrantup.com/&#34;&gt;Vagrant&lt;/a&gt; plugin whichautomatically installs the host&#39;s VirtualBox Guest Additions on the guestsystem.&lt;/p&gt;</description><link>https://mike.bailey.net.au/blog/2012/10/06/vagrant-notes/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=feed-syndication</link> <pubDate>Sat, 06 Oct 2012 12:38:25 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://mike.bailey.net.au/feed_rss_created.xml">mbailey/notes</source><comments>https://mike.bailey.net.au/blog/2012/10/06/vagrant-notes/#__comments</comments><guid isPermaLink="true">https://mike.bailey.net.au/blog/2012/10/06/vagrant-notes/</guid> </item> <item> <title>First Impressions of Macbook Air with preinstalled Mountain Lion</title> <author>mbailey</author> <description>&lt;p&gt;Last Friday night I picked up my new Macbook Pro and thought it might be worthsharing my initial experiences. Coming from a late 2011 MacBook Pro with HDDI&#39;m loving the speed and lighter form factor.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2 id=&#34;mac-osx-mountain-lion-demotes-usrlocalbin-in-path&#34;&gt;Mac OSX Mountain Lion demotes /usr/local/bin in path&lt;a class=&#34;headerlink&#34; href=&#34;#mac-osx-mountain-lion-demotes-usrlocalbin-in-path&#34; title=&#34;Permanent link&#34;&gt;&amp;para;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Homebrew&#39;s &#39;brew doctor&#39; command warned me about my PATH.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;Warning: /usr/bin occurs before /usr/local/bin&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;This means that system-provided programs will be used instead of thoseprovided by Homebrew.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;It turns out /etc/paths has listed last /usr/local/bin. Ever since reading DanBenjamin&#39;s post, &lt;a href=&#34;http://hivelogic.com/articles/using_usr_local/&#34;&gt;Using /usr/local&lt;/a&gt; I&#39;vebeen...erm...using /usr/local. I&#39;d be interested to know why Apple made thischange.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2 id=&#34;macgpg2-can-mess-with-libiconv&#34;&gt;MacGPG2 can mess with libiconv&lt;a class=&#34;headerlink&#34; href=&#34;#macgpg2-can-mess-with-libiconv&#34; title=&#34;Permanent link&#34;&gt;&amp;para;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;While on the topic of PATHs, you don&#39;t want this in your PATH: /usr/local/MacGPG2/bin&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;For some reason this was the cause of me being unable to compile nativeextensions in the tiny_tds rubygem. GCC appears to have been grabbing that itemand then finding /usr/local/MacGPG2/include/iconv.h which conflicted with theOSX installed version. (Brew tells me the package is no longer provided as OSXprovides libiconv).&lt;/p&gt;</description><link>https://mike.bailey.net.au/blog/2012/09/27/first-impressions-of-macbook-air-with-preinstalled-mountain-lion/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=feed-syndication</link> <pubDate>Thu, 27 Sep 2012 01:30:40 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://mike.bailey.net.au/feed_rss_created.xml">mbailey/notes</source><comments>https://mike.bailey.net.au/blog/2012/09/27/first-impressions-of-macbook-air-with-preinstalled-mountain-lion/#__comments</comments><guid isPermaLink="true">https://mike.bailey.net.au/blog/2012/09/27/first-impressions-of-macbook-air-with-preinstalled-mountain-lion/</guid> </item> <item> <title>Oil Lamps in the Geek House</title> <author>mbailey</author> <category>lifehacking</category> <category>light</category> <category>tldr</category> <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;Connect It by Chow Hon Lam&#34; src=&#34;../../../../images/2012-08-11-oil-lamps-geek-house/636x460design_01-300x216.jpeg&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Of the five senses, the two I get most signal through are sight and hearing.Over the past few weeks I&#39;ve been experimenting with the former and have madesome interesting discoveries (or perhaps more correctly, rediscoveries). I haveno qualifications in lighting or biological science but think it&#39;s worthsharing my experiences and a summary of what I&#39;ve learned. I&#39;d love to hearfrom you (in the comments) if you find any of it interesting.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;People&#39;s sensitivity to their environment varies greatly. I think I&#39;m on themore sensitive end of the spectrum and are more affected by:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Glare_%28vision%29&#34;&gt;glare&lt;/a&gt; - halogen down-lights, car headlights in the rear view mirror&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Color_temperature&#34;&gt;color temperature&lt;/a&gt; - evening computer use, walking into convenience stores lit by fluorescent lights&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Golden_hour_%28photography%29&#34;&gt;golden hour&lt;/a&gt; - first/last hour of sunlight loved by photographers and film makers&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;firelight - candle, oil lamp, campfire&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-lamp-shop&#34;&gt;The Lamp Shop&lt;a class=&#34;headerlink&#34; href=&#34;#the-lamp-shop&#34; title=&#34;Permanent link&#34;&gt;&amp;para;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://talesofbrickandmortar.com/2018/02/20/t-w-sands-and-co-est-1918/&#34;&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;T.W. Sands, Melbourne (1918-2018)&#34; src=&#34;../../../../images/2012-08-11-oil-lamps-geek-house/lamp_shop.jpeg&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;As a teen I went through a phase of lighting candles in my bedroom. The lightthey produced created a different mood or atmosphere that I think most readerswill relate to. A few weeks ago when walking home from the Melbourne CBD I cameacross a curious little lamp shop that would not have looked out of place acentury ago.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Established in 1918 and in Elizabeth Street from 1951 to 2004, T.W. Sands &amp;amp; Cois one of the few original lamp houses left in the world.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;T.W. Sands &amp;amp; Co has been selling oil and kerosene lamps for almost 100 years.They never switched to electricity! Inside they sell new and old lamps, as wellas wicks, chimneys, oil and replacement parts. My curious mind lit up withquestions - fortunately the staff have a detailed knowledge of the workings ofthe lamps along with the history of advancements in burner technology. Inshort, the Americans won the arms race with the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.aladdinlamps.com/&#34;&gt;40 candle powerAladdin&lt;/a&gt; which is still in production today. Thisuses a &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Thermoluminescence&#34;&gt;thermoluminescentmantle&lt;/a&gt; that throws off abright white light when heated by the burner. They&#39;re so bright they require ashade to reduce glare and while great for a dinner table I prefer my flamesnaked.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2 id=&#34;oil-powered-time-machine&#34;&gt;Oil Powered Time Machine&lt;a class=&#34;headerlink&#34; href=&#34;#oil-powered-time-machine&#34; title=&#34;Permanent link&#34;&gt;&amp;para;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;I returned the next day to buy three different types of lamp for my 1880&#39;s homein Carlton North. The house sports three rather impressive fireplaces thatwould have been the main source of heating when built. The mantle pieces seemedlike an obvious place to put the lamps. They stand at shoulder height and are afoot deep which means the lamps:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;are in an optimal position to light faces&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;illuminate the other things on the mantlepiece, creating a feature&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;probably most importantly, won&#39;t get knocked over by an arm or bag hanging from someone&#39;s shoulder&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;This last point is important. A number of people expressed alarm that I wasusing firelight in my house, fearing an accident. While I don&#39;t think lamp oilwill burn on floorboards, a rug, curtains or other wick-like furnishing wouldbe happy to assist and I could imagine many a housefire was started by a lamp.The clumsy and dim witted are probably better off in a fire free household. I&#39;mconfident I can manage it though. Already I felt like I was defending somethingthat few would have worried about in the 1880s.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;the time machine&#34; src=&#34;../../../../images/2012-08-11-oil-lamps-geek-house/the_time_machine_large_01-1-300x256.jpeg&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I decided to do a sort of &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.earthhour.org/&#34;&gt;Earth Hour&lt;/a&gt; on steroids,abstaining from electric lighting for a week. The experience transported meback to a time where the human experience of night time was very different towhat we know today. For someone with little practical experience usingfirelight in a domestic environment I had to work things out for myself. Thiswas interesting from a historical perspective but also led to me learning moreabout how our eyes work and the magic of night vision.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In some ways it felt like camping, perhaps because that&#39;s the only time Iexperience the night without electric lights. For this experiment I had acontrol - the house as I used it before - so I could identify what elements ofthe experience were due to the lighting. This removed confounding variableslike country air, a long drive and kangaroos.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2 id=&#34;firelight-changes-the-user-interface-of-a-room&#34;&gt;Firelight Changes the User Interface of a Room&lt;a class=&#34;headerlink&#34; href=&#34;#firelight-changes-the-user-interface-of-a-room&#34; title=&#34;Permanent link&#34;&gt;&amp;para;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Back in the late 90&#39;s Google replaced Alta Vista as the search engine of choice.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;Alta Vista got &#39;busy&#39;&#34; src=&#34;../../../../images/2012-08-11-oil-lamps-geek-house/AltaVista-HOME-280x300.jpg&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;One refreshing change was the lack of distractions on the Google&#39;s search page.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;Google&#39;s distraction free interface&#34; src=&#34;../../../../images/2012-08-11-oil-lamps-geek-house/Google-300x183.jpg&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Modern home lighting is akin to flood lighting. The majority of homes haveoverhead lighting without dimmers which results in reflected (and lots of it)light being pretty evenly dispersed. Firelight is of lower intensity and sohighlights things in close proximity. You wouldn&#39;t clean the floors tofirelight - that&#39;s a job better left for the cold light of day. Similarly, it&#39;snot as easy to check for mud on your boots in firelight. I wouldn&#39;t besurprised if people we more inclined to leave them at the front door if theycame home after dark.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Low output lights seems to create less extraneous stimulus by creating morefocus on areas nearer the light source.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2 id=&#34;ow-my-eyes&#34;&gt;Ow! My Eyes!&lt;a class=&#34;headerlink&#34; href=&#34;#ow-my-eyes&#34; title=&#34;Permanent link&#34;&gt;&amp;para;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;In addition to the lower intensity of firelight, it also gives has a muchwarmer colour temperature. At the opposite end of the spectrum is the lightyou&#39;re confronted with when visiting a convenience store litby fluorescent tubes.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;Worst mood lighting ever&#34; src=&#34;../../../../images/2012-08-11-oil-lamps-geek-house/franchise_7-eleven-300x203.gif&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Color Temperature is measured in Kelvin and strangely enough a lower valuerefers to a warmer light. It refers to the temperature of a black body radiatorthat emits a light of comparable hue. The &#39;cold light of day&#39; is up therewith fluorescent tubes which might explain why walking into one at night can befeel so unpleasant. Suddenly adjusting to a different color temperature seemsto be a bit jarring for some people.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;table&gt;&lt;thead&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;th&gt;Temperature (K)&lt;/th&gt;&lt;th&gt;Source&lt;/th&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/thead&gt;&lt;tbody&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;1,700&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;Match flame&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;1,850&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;Candle flame, sunset/sunrise&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;2,700–3,300&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;Incandescent lamps&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;3,000&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;Soft White compact fluorescent lamps&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;3,200&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;Studio lamps, photofloods, etc.&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;3,350&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt; Studio &#34;CP&#34; light&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;4,100–4,150&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt; Moonlight,&lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Color_temperature#cite_note-1&#34;&gt;[2]&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Xenon_arc_lamp&#34;&gt;xenon arc lamp&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;5,000&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt; Horizon daylight&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;5,000&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt; tubular fluorescent lamps or Cool White/Daylight compact fluorescent lamps (CFL)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;5,500–6,000&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt; Vertical daylight, electronic flash&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;6,500&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt; Daylight, overcast&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;6,500–9,300&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt; LCD or CRT screen&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;15,000–27,000&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt; Clear blue northern sky&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/tbody&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;p&gt;Golden Hour (sunset/sunrise) is well known to photographers and film makers forwhom light quality is critical. While factors such as smog can have an impact,generally the light at this time has a color temperature closer to firelight. Itook to walking my dogs at this time and in addition to watching the sun lightup the clouds noticed the changes in the way it lights everything during thattime. It&#39;s also referred to as Magic Hour and I highly recommend it as a greattime to take a walk outside.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Something you can do right now to make your computing life nicer is to install &lt;a href=&#34;http://stereopsis.com/flux/&#34;&gt;f.lux&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;&#34;Ever notice how people texting at night have that &lt;strong&gt;eerie blue glow&lt;/strong&gt;? Orwake up ready to write down the Next Great Idea, and get blinded by yourcomputer screen? During the day, computer screens look good—they&#39;re designedto &lt;strong&gt;look like the sun&lt;/strong&gt;. But, at 9PM, 10PM, or 3AM, you probably shouldn&#39;tbe looking at the sun.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;F.lux fixes this: it makes the color of your computer&#39;s display adapt to thetime of day, warm at night and like sunlight during the day.It&#39;s evenpossible that you&#39;re staying up too late because of your computer. You coulduse f.lux because it makes you sleep better, or you could just use it justbecause it makes your computer look better.&#34; - &lt;a href=&#34;http://stereopsis.com/flux/&#34;&gt;f.lux website&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;h2 id=&#34;night-vision&#34;&gt;Night Vision&lt;a class=&#34;headerlink&#34; href=&#34;#night-vision&#34; title=&#34;Permanent link&#34;&gt;&amp;para;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Walking the dogs at sunset led to a surprising discovery. On returning home Ineeded to enter the house in the dark to light my lamps. (I&#39;m pretty surepeople used to keep a hand lamp on the hall stand to make this taskeasier/safer!). On returning home one evening I discovered I could navigatereasonably well using just the light entering my windows from the night sky andstreet lighting.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;&#34;Rhodopsin is the chemical that allows night-vision, and is extremelysensitive to light. Exposed to a spectrum of light, the pigment immediatelybleaches, and it takes about 30 minutes to regenerate fully, but most ofthe &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Adaptation_%28eye%29&#34;&gt;adaptation&lt;/a&gt;) occurs withinthe first five or ten minutes in the dark.&#34; Wikipedia&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;image&#34; src=&#34;../../../../images/2012-08-11-oil-lamps-geek-house/208778-300x300.jpeg&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Like an anemone, night vision is super sensitive to disturbances, quick toretreat and slow to return.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;&#34;The human eye can function from very dark to very bright levels of light;its sensing capabilities reach across nine &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Order_of_magnitude&#34;&gt;orders ofmagnitude&lt;/a&gt;. This means thatthe brightest and the darkest light signal that the eye can sense are afactor of roughly 1,000,000,000 apart. However, in any given moment of time,the eye can only sensea &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Contrast_%28vision%29&#34;&gt;contrast&lt;/a&gt;) ratio of onethousand. What enables the wider reach is that the eye adapts its definitionof what is black. The light level that is interpreted as &#34;black&#34; can beshifted across six orders of magnitude—a factor of one million.&#34;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Adaptation_%28eye%29&#34;&gt;Wikipedia entry to Adaptation (eye)&lt;/a&gt;) - Note that it does not contain a citation!&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;Firelight doesn&#39;t seem to blow away my night vision. When I walk out into the backyard I can see pretty well.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2 id=&#34;how-low-light-can-you-go&#34;&gt;How Low (Light) Can You Go&lt;a class=&#34;headerlink&#34; href=&#34;#how-low-light-can-you-go&#34; title=&#34;Permanent link&#34;&gt;&amp;para;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;The idea that my eyes had a contrast ratio of 1000 but that I could potentiallysense across nine orders of magnitude led me to try to create a darkroom in myhouse. In short I failed to stop all light from entering my living room. Atfirst it appears that the bin liners taped to the windows had worked but as myadaptation progressed I could see lighter patches on the windows where the binliners were not doubled over. Reflected light from the ski was seeping through!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;That said, the light getting in was not enough to allow me to see my hand infront of my face - the quintessential measure of darkness. My hand was visibleif a held a lit cigarette close to it but not when I moved it a foot away. Iwas amazed at how sensitive my eyes were to light in such a low lightenvironment. How much light does a lit cigarette emit? I would love to know ifthat&#39;s been measured!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Looking around the room I could see what looked like light seeping under thedoor. This light originated from the street, passed through the window in myfront door and then down a long hallway. It occurred to me that in this modernera it&#39;s almost impossible to keep light out.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;To Be Continued?&lt;/p&gt;</description><link>https://mike.bailey.net.au/blog/2012/08/11/oil-lamps-geek-house/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=feed-syndication</link> <pubDate>Sat, 11 Aug 2012 10:56:26 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://mike.bailey.net.au/feed_rss_created.xml">mbailey/notes</source><comments>https://mike.bailey.net.au/blog/2012/08/11/oil-lamps-geek-house/#__comments</comments><guid isPermaLink="true">https://mike.bailey.net.au/blog/2012/08/11/oil-lamps-geek-house/</guid> </item> <item> <title>Personal Cloudification</title> <author>mbailey</author> <category>amazon</category> <category>cloud</category> <category>host@home</category> <category>systems</category> <category>virtualization</category> <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-urge-to-own&#34;&gt;The Urge to Own...&lt;a class=&#34;headerlink&#34; href=&#34;#the-urge-to-own&#34; title=&#34;Permanent link&#34;&gt;&amp;para;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;Expensive Paperweights&#34; src=&#34;../../../../images/2012-07-03-personal-cloudification/IMG_2241-225x300.jpg&#34; /&gt;&lt;em&gt;Expensive Paperweights&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Something about my personality has seen me always running my own servers. Inthe late 90s I setup a Pentium 100 with a permanent 28.8 kbps modem connectionto the Internet in a wardrobe at my parents house. It hosted my mail and webservices for a few years (including 18 months spent living in the U.K.).Something about knowing the system down to the metal, and beyond that even, tothe environment has always been important to me. I think amongst systems peopleI&#39;m not alone.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2 id=&#34;versus-the-allure-of-the-cloud&#34;&gt;... versus the Allure of The Cloud&lt;a class=&#34;headerlink&#34; href=&#34;#versus-the-allure-of-the-cloud&#34; title=&#34;Permanent link&#34;&gt;&amp;para;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Various factors have led me to abandon (at least for now) my desire to&lt;a href=&#34;../../../../2011/04/11/hosthome-setting-up-your-network/&#34;&gt;host@home&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;power consumption (waste &amp;amp; cost) &amp;amp; heat output&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;single points of failure (power, ADSL, theft)&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;desire to eat my own dogfood&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;A few years back I found other services to be cheaper than Amazon&#39;s AWSofferings. I&#39;m currently exploring what has changed since then and howindividuals can use Amazon AWS to provide performant, highly available Internetservices at low cost.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2 id=&#34;mobile-is-changing-everything&#34;&gt;Mobile is Changing Everything&lt;a class=&#34;headerlink&#34; href=&#34;#mobile-is-changing-everything&#34; title=&#34;Permanent link&#34;&gt;&amp;para;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;There are some great tools out there for controlling your Amazon services frommobile devices. Cloud Services Manager is a great app for iOS that enablescontrol of AWS services on the go. My SSH client of choice for connecting fromiOS is &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.panic.com/blog/2011/04/introducing-prompt-ssh-for-ios/&#34;&gt;Prompt by Panic,Inc&lt;/a&gt;. Thesetwo alone let give you a lot of control from your iPhone (or iPad).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;Cloud Services Manager for iPhone&#34; src=&#34;../../../../images/2012-07-03-personal-cloudification/IMG_2247-200x300.png&#34; /&gt;&lt;em&gt;Cloud Services Manager for iPhone&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;Create, start, stop EC2 instances&#34; src=&#34;../../../../images/2012-07-03-personal-cloudification/IMG_2245-200x300.png&#34; /&gt;&lt;em&gt;Create, start, stop EC2 instances&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;Cloudwatch Stats&#34; src=&#34;../../../../images/2012-07-03-personal-cloudification/IMG_2246-200x300.png&#34; /&gt;&lt;em&gt;Cloudwatch Stats&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;Prompt SSH client for iOS&#34; src=&#34;../../../../images/2012-07-03-personal-cloudification/IMG_2248-200x300.png&#34; /&gt;&lt;em&gt;Prompt SSH client for iOS&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;Prompt is remarkably usable&#34; src=&#34;../../../../images/2012-07-03-personal-cloudification/IMG_2249-200x300.png&#34; /&gt;&lt;em&gt;Prompt is remarkably usable&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;ASCII steam locomotive (sl)&#34; src=&#34;../../../../images/2012-07-03-personal-cloudification/IMG_2250-200x300.png&#34; /&gt;&lt;em&gt;ASCII steam locomotive (sl)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;br style=&#34;clear: both&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2 id=&#34;cost-savings-in-dev-land&#34;&gt;Cost Savings in Dev Land&lt;a class=&#34;headerlink&#34; href=&#34;#cost-savings-in-dev-land&#34; title=&#34;Permanent link&#34;&gt;&amp;para;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;When EC2 was first launched you lost everything if you shut an instance down.These days Elastic Block Store (EBS) volumes are the default which means youcan stop and restart instances as you need them, paying only for the hoursthey&#39;re running. This can make it more comfortable to tinker knowing you&#39;reonly paying while you&#39;re using it. Running 10 x m1.small instances will cost$0.80 an hour which is quite affordable.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Note that you&#39;re charged by the month for the EBS volume the instance uses. Thecharge includes a charge of approx. &lt;a href=&#34;http://aws.amazon.com/pricing/ebs/&#34;&gt;$0.10 per GB-month of provisionedstorage and $0.10 per 1 million I/Orequests&lt;/a&gt;. I believe that creating a 10 GBEBS volume and destroying it an hour later would be counted as 10 GB-months butI want to confirm (or refute) this.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;To Be Continued...&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><link>https://mike.bailey.net.au/blog/2012/07/03/personal-cloudification/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=feed-syndication</link> <pubDate>Tue, 03 Jul 2012 15:08:39 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://mike.bailey.net.au/feed_rss_created.xml">mbailey/notes</source><comments>https://mike.bailey.net.au/blog/2012/07/03/personal-cloudification/#__comments</comments><guid isPermaLink="true">https://mike.bailey.net.au/blog/2012/07/03/personal-cloudification/</guid> </item> <item> <title>I saw robots! - My Tour of Toyota</title> <author>mbailey</author> <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;Robots welding car bodies at Toyota plant in Altona&#34; src=&#34;../../../../images/2012-06-28-i-saw-robots-my-tour-of-toyota/3789570-3x2-940x627.jpeg&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Today I did the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.gizmodo.com.au/2009/09/the-toyota-altona-factory-tour-cars-robots-and-muzak/&#34;&gt;Toyota Altona plant tour&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The tour was exciting and enjoyable. My favourite moment was when our guidepushed away a pinboard to reveal a line of eight cars beingoperated on by large welding robots. Sparks were flying in what musthave been dangerous work when humans did it.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I think it will take a couple of nights to decompress anddigest the information - there was a lot to take in - buthere are some initial observations:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Assembly line workers perform a very different profile of work to knowledge workers. Wherever possible they seem to have been replaced with machines.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Humans are required on the line for processes where increased levels of dexterity, mobility, visual perception or tactile ability are required.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;The robots and humans seem to get along well. When humans stop for morning tea the unmanned vehicles that carry parts around go and charge themselves.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Quality Circles - staff can form a quality circle if they believe there is an improvement that can be made to process. There is a well defined structure to the process which helps staff participate in modifying the process.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;The system is incredibly well run but we saw very few &#34;screens&#34;. Reports and graphs were printed and pinned on boards. Dynamic status boards were painted with coloured lights to indicate status. A large board would have a similar level of visual detail to an iPhone app. Simplicity!&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;The work environment was sympathetic to the humans in it. Noise wasn&#39;t excessive and they used music to signal problems on a line.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;If staff climb into a machine they put a lock with their name and photo on it - a great safeguard that makes workers responsible for their own safety.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;</description><link>https://mike.bailey.net.au/blog/2012/06/28/i-saw-robots-my-tour-of-toyota/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=feed-syndication</link> <pubDate>Thu, 28 Jun 2012 06:57:38 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://mike.bailey.net.au/feed_rss_created.xml">mbailey/notes</source><comments>https://mike.bailey.net.au/blog/2012/06/28/i-saw-robots-my-tour-of-toyota/#__comments</comments><guid isPermaLink="true">https://mike.bailey.net.au/blog/2012/06/28/i-saw-robots-my-tour-of-toyota/</guid> </item> <item> <title>EC2 Outage: Pimp my Fail</title> <author>mbailey</author> <category>amazon</category> <category>cloud</category> <category>ec2</category> <category>heroku</category> <description>&lt;p&gt;Amazon are reporting degraded performance for some volumes in a single AZ inthe us-east-1 region.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://status.aws.amazon.com/&#34;&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;AWS Service Health Dashboard&#34; src=&#34;../../../../images/2012-06-15-ec2-outage-pimp-my-fail/AWS-Service-Health-Dashboard-Jun-14-2012-1.jpg&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Twitter has lit up with complaints. An amusing one referred to &#34;&lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/#!/search/elastic%20sla&#34;&gt;AmazonsElastic SLA&lt;/a&gt;&#34;. Overheard in theoffice &#34;The Cloud&#39;s down! Does that mean it&#39;s sunny?&#34;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2 id=&#34;fire-drill-for-the-cloud-or-youre-doing-it-wrong&#34;&gt;Fire Drill for the Cloud or You&#39;re Doing it Wrong&lt;a class=&#34;headerlink&#34; href=&#34;#fire-drill-for-the-cloud-or-youre-doing-it-wrong&#34; title=&#34;Permanent link&#34;&gt;&amp;para;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Some pretty high profile websites are timing out which seems to indicate we&#39;renot the only ones to have failed to take advantage of the high availabilitymade possible by the AWS service stack.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;More concerning though is the lack of design effort put into their error pages.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;Heroku Gateway Timeout&#34; src=&#34;../../../../images/2012-06-15-ec2-outage-pimp-my-fail/heroku-504-Gateway-Time-out-1.jpg&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.quora.com/&#34;&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;Quora Error&#34; src=&#34;../../../../images/2012-06-15-ec2-outage-pimp-my-fail/quora.com_.jpg&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2 id=&#34;take-a-lesson-from-the-masters&#34;&gt;Take a Lesson from the Masters&lt;a class=&#34;headerlink&#34; href=&#34;#take-a-lesson-from-the-masters&#34; title=&#34;Permanent link&#34;&gt;&amp;para;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;GitHub put the fun back into fail, like the sound effects on TV&#39;s Funniest Home Videos.&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/504.html&#34;&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;GitHub 404&#34; src=&#34;../../../../images/2012-06-15-ec2-outage-pimp-my-fail/404.jpg&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;My all time favourite 404 page captures the awkward embarrassment on an unsatisfiable request.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://visitsteve.com/404.html&#34;&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;Visit Steve 404&#34; src=&#34;../../../../images/2012-06-15-ec2-outage-pimp-my-fail/visit-steve-404.jpg&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><link>https://mike.bailey.net.au/blog/2012/06/15/ec2-outage-pimp-my-fail/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=feed-syndication</link> <pubDate>Fri, 15 Jun 2012 04:48:11 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://mike.bailey.net.au/feed_rss_created.xml">mbailey/notes</source><comments>https://mike.bailey.net.au/blog/2012/06/15/ec2-outage-pimp-my-fail/#__comments</comments><guid isPermaLink="true">https://mike.bailey.net.au/blog/2012/06/15/ec2-outage-pimp-my-fail/</guid> </item> <item> <title>iPads are just made for Screencasts</title> <author>mbailey</author> <category>apple</category> <category>presentations</category> <category>productivity</category> <category>ruby on rails</category> <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;killer-app-for-ipads&#34;&gt;Killer app for iPads&lt;a class=&#34;headerlink&#34; href=&#34;#killer-app-for-ipads&#34; title=&#34;Permanent link&#34;&gt;&amp;para;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Trying to justify getting yourself a new iPad3? My favourite use for my iPadlately has been watching quality screencasts by Gary Bernhardt (Destroy AllSoftware) and Ryan Bates (RailsCasts). Each offer a premium subscription modelwhere you pay $9 a month for access to their full catalog along with all newvideos.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I&#39;ve never really been into Screencasts but I&#39;ve only recently discovered thesecret seems to be in keeping them short. Here are two I&#39;ve been really gettinginto.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2 id=&#34;worth-paying-for&#34;&gt;Worth Paying For&lt;a class=&#34;headerlink&#34; href=&#34;#worth-paying-for&#34; title=&#34;Permanent link&#34;&gt;&amp;para;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;How much do you earn each month from your craft? I wouldn&#39;t think twice aboutpaying $9 a month to the individuals who create such valuable art. To be honestI think we&#39;re getting it cheap.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2 id=&#34;destroy-all-software&#34;&gt;Destroy All Software&lt;a class=&#34;headerlink&#34; href=&#34;#destroy-all-software&#34; title=&#34;Permanent link&#34;&gt;&amp;para;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Gary Bernhardt has a communication style I can only describe it as &#34;performancevim&#34;. You spend most of the ten or so minutes watching him make text dance in afull screen terminal. It&#39;s like pairing with someone you can really learnsomething from. The iPad is just the right size to make it work.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.destroyallsoftware.com/screencasts&#34;&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;Destroy All Software Screencasts&#34; src=&#34;../../../../images/2012-03-06-ipads-are-made-for-screencasts/Destroy-All-Software-Screencasts-1.jpg&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;Destroy All Software Screencasts&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2 id=&#34;railscasts&#34;&gt;RailsCasts&lt;a class=&#34;headerlink&#34; href=&#34;#railscasts&#34; title=&#34;Permanent link&#34;&gt;&amp;para;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Ryan Bates has been producing short (5-12 minute) screencasts covering allmanner of topics of interest to &#34;Ruby People&#34; for years now and making themavailable &lt;strong&gt;for free&lt;/strong&gt;. Ryan makes his screencasts available via RSS whichmeans they automatically find their way to my iPad.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Too many in our community give of themselves without making it easy enough forus to give back. I contacted Ryan a while back to ask how I could donate. I&#39;mglad he has now made restructured things to make his ongoing work sustainable.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://railscasts.com/&#34;&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;Ryan Bates has been producing quality RailsCasts for years now&#34; src=&#34;../../../../images/2012-03-06-ipads-are-made-for-screencasts/Ruby-on-Rails-Screencasts-RailsCasts.jpg&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;Ryan Bates has been producing quality RailsCasts for years now&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><link>https://mike.bailey.net.au/blog/2012/03/06/ipads-are-made-for-screencasts/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=feed-syndication</link> <pubDate>Tue, 06 Mar 2012 10:34:52 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://mike.bailey.net.au/feed_rss_created.xml">mbailey/notes</source><comments>https://mike.bailey.net.au/blog/2012/03/06/ipads-are-made-for-screencasts/#__comments</comments><guid isPermaLink="true">https://mike.bailey.net.au/blog/2012/03/06/ipads-are-made-for-screencasts/</guid> </item> <item> <title>Why We Automate</title> <author>mbailey</author> <category>devops</category> <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;Manual&#34; src=&#34;../../../../images/20plush.jpeg&#34; /&gt;&lt;em&gt;Manual&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;Automated&#34; src=&#34;../../../../images/snack-vending-machines.jpeg&#34; /&gt;&lt;em&gt;Automated&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><link>https://mike.bailey.net.au/blog/2012/01/22/why-we-automate/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=feed-syndication</link> <pubDate>Sun, 22 Jan 2012 01:13:32 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://mike.bailey.net.au/feed_rss_created.xml">mbailey/notes</source><comments>https://mike.bailey.net.au/blog/2012/01/22/why-we-automate/#__comments</comments><guid isPermaLink="true">https://mike.bailey.net.au/blog/2012/01/22/why-we-automate/</guid> </item> <item> <title>Back To My Mac, Confessions of a Reluctant Apostate</title> <author>mbailey</author> <category>apple</category> <category>productivity</category> <category>psychology</category> <category>systems</category> <description>&lt;h3 id=&#34;rethinking-fanboyism&#34;&gt;Rethinking Fanboyism&lt;a class=&#34;headerlink&#34; href=&#34;#rethinking-fanboyism&#34; title=&#34;Permanent link&#34;&gt;&amp;para;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Two years after replacing my Apple Macbook Pro laptop with a Dell runningUbuntu Linux I&#39;m going back to Apple. I moved away from Apple for a mixture ofphilosophical and practical reasons. One of the main reasons was my belief inthe importance of a viable linux desktop operating system. The backflip cameabout because I feel happier when using Apple products. In my attempts to getaway from Apple I think I&#39;ve learned more about why they have been sosuccessful.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3 id=&#34;android-was-the-catalyst&#34;&gt;Android was the Catalyst&lt;a class=&#34;headerlink&#34; href=&#34;#android-was-the-catalyst&#34; title=&#34;Permanent link&#34;&gt;&amp;para;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;I didn&#39;t get a smartphone until mid 2011 and even then it was mainly becausethe battery on my Nokia was needing to be charged nightly. I picked up an HTCSensation and began hating it almost immediately. I&#39;m usually pretty good atpointing out flaws but the HTC was a bit of a mystery to me. While I can list afew flaws (battery not lasting a day is one!) I just didn&#39;t like using it.After three months I decided to buy my first iPhone.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3 id=&#34;i-feel-love&#34;&gt;I Feel Love&lt;a class=&#34;headerlink&#34; href=&#34;#i-feel-love&#34; title=&#34;Permanent link&#34;&gt;&amp;para;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;So this is the fucked up thing. Within 30 minutes I was texting people to tellthem how much I love my new iPhone. It may make me sound like a total fanboybut even while I was in the store I was bonding with the device. It feels wrongsaying I love a machine but  at the same time I&#39;m curious how it could elicitsuch emotions. I can only put it down to the design of both hardware andsoftware.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-cathedral-and-the-bazaar&#34;&gt;The Cathedral and The Bazaar&lt;a class=&#34;headerlink&#34; href=&#34;#the-cathedral-and-the-bazaar&#34; title=&#34;Permanent link&#34;&gt;&amp;para;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Steve Jobs was the high priest at Apple. We&#39;re told he was obsessive aboutdetail and that it was his way or the highway. Part of the reason I avoidedgetting an iPhone was the control exerted over the distribution of Apps throughthe App Store. I was surprised and disappointed by my first experience of theAndroid Marketplace. A search for &#34;shopping list&#34; returned hundreds of appswith no indication which were most downloaded or highly rated. Maybe you can&#39;tdesign an OS or phone by committee?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3 id=&#34;get-out-of-my-way&#34;&gt;Get Out of my Way&lt;a class=&#34;headerlink&#34; href=&#34;#get-out-of-my-way&#34; title=&#34;Permanent link&#34;&gt;&amp;para;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;If I&#39;m going to be iPhone boy then life would be easier if I used OSX on my desktop.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;It&#39;s been about 4 years since I last bought a new Macbook Pro. My efforts toavoid vendor lockin are now being replaced by efforts to avoid unproductivework (like debugging problems printing from Ubuntu 11.10). I want to get onwith the fun stuff and OSX just seems to make the fun stuff so much easier.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3 id=&#34;so-what-now-for-freedom&#34;&gt;So What Now for Freedom?&lt;a class=&#34;headerlink&#34; href=&#34;#so-what-now-for-freedom&#34; title=&#34;Permanent link&#34;&gt;&amp;para;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;I was shocked earlier this year to hear a techie say he wouldn&#39;t care if thelinux desktop went away because he&#39;s happy with OSX. My issue is that Applecould make OSX unpleasant at some point in the future and without a viablealternative to switch to we would just have to accept it.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I don&#39;t think me going back to Apple is going to make an ounce of difference toLinux but what would the world be like if everyone followed this path? I guessI&#39;m no longer willing to sacrifice my own happiness trying to support thisparticular ideal.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3 id=&#34;well-done-steve-and-company&#34;&gt;Well Done Steve (and Company)&lt;a class=&#34;headerlink&#34; href=&#34;#well-done-steve-and-company&#34; title=&#34;Permanent link&#34;&gt;&amp;para;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;The iPhone and Macbook Pro are masterpieces. (I didn&#39;t mention I&#39;ve had an iPadfor the past 12 months and love it to bits). I tried to extract myself fromthis web of awesome production but have failed because they are so welldesigned. I would love to create something as compelling.&lt;/p&gt;</description><link>https://mike.bailey.net.au/blog/2011/11/18/back-to-my-mac-confessions-of-a-reluctant-apostate/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=feed-syndication</link> <pubDate>Fri, 18 Nov 2011 13:45:41 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://mike.bailey.net.au/feed_rss_created.xml">mbailey/notes</source><comments>https://mike.bailey.net.au/blog/2011/11/18/back-to-my-mac-confessions-of-a-reluctant-apostate/#__comments</comments><guid isPermaLink="true">https://mike.bailey.net.au/blog/2011/11/18/back-to-my-mac-confessions-of-a-reluctant-apostate/</guid> </item> </channel></rss>